<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><anime id="26" restricted="false">
<type>TV Series</type>
<episodecount>45</episodecount>
<startdate>2002-04-09</startdate>
<enddate>2003-08-30</enddate>
<titles>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="main">Juuni Kokuki</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="synonym">Juuni Kokki</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="synonym">Record of 12 countries</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="synonym">12 Kingdoms</title>
<title xml:lang="ru" type="synonym">Хроники Двенадцати Королевств</title>
<title xml:lang="pl" type="synonym">12 królestw</title>
<title xml:lang="pl" type="synonym">Dwanaście królestw</title>
<title xml:lang="ar" type="synonym">الممالك الاثنى عشر</title>
<title xml:lang="pt-BR" type="synonym">Doze Reinos</title>
<title xml:lang="cs" type="synonym">Dvanáct království</title>
<title xml:lang="lt" type="synonym">12 Karalysčių</title>
<title xml:lang="th" type="synonym">12 อาณาจักรเทพยุทธ์</title>
<title xml:lang="tr" type="synonym">12 Krallık</title>
<title xml:lang="ro" type="synonym">12 Împărăţii</title>
<title xml:lang="bg" type="synonym">Дванадесете Кралства</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="synonym">12 Kokuki</title>
<title xml:lang="et" type="synonym">Kaksteist Kuningriiki</title>
<title xml:lang="uk" type="synonym">Хроніки дванадцяти королівств</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="short">12K</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">JK</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">Juuni</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="official">十二国記</title>
<title xml:lang="zh" type="official">十二国记</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="official">The Twelve Kingdoms</title>
<title xml:lang="de" type="official">12 Kingdoms - Juuni Kokki</title>
<title xml:lang="fr" type="official">Les 12 royaumes</title>
<title xml:lang="es" type="official">Doce Reinos</title>
<title xml:lang="ru" type="official">Двенадцать королевств</title>
<title xml:lang="pt-BR" type="official">The Twelve Kingdoms</title>
<title xml:lang="ca" type="official">Els Dotze Regnes</title>
<title xml:lang="he" type="official">שתים עשרה הממלכות</title>
<title xml:lang="es-LA" type="official">Los Doce Reinos</title>
</titles>
<similaranime>
<anime id="4403" approval="225" total="263">Seirei no Moribito</anime>
<anime id="4150" approval="95" total="117">Saiunkoku Monogatari</anime>
<anime id="184" approval="92" total="119">Tenkuu no Escaflowne</anime>
<anime id="6187" approval="82" total="139">Kemono no Souja Erin</anime>
<anime id="5024" approval="61" total="77">Saiunkoku Monogatari 2nd Series</anime>
<anime id="10725" approval="27" total="33">Akatsuki no Yona: The Girl Standing in the Blush of Dawn</anime>
<anime id="3427" approval="20" total="40">Utawarerumono</anime>
<anime id="519" approval="17" total="22">Arslan Senki</anime>
<anime id="87" approval="16" total="32">Fushigi Yuugi</anime>
<anime id="640" approval="7" total="27">Scrapped Princess</anime>
<anime id="1677" approval="7" total="15">Kyou kara Maou!</anime>
<anime id="6331" approval="6" total="16">Guin Saga</anime>
<anime id="8869" approval="1" total="11">Oda Nobuna no Yabou</anime>
</similaranime>
<recommendations total="67">
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="494291">Slow start, overload of unique lore terminology sounding way too similar, and telling too little over the span of 45 episodes, of which 3 eps are recaps. Main character development is nice. You may enjoy this if you like heavy fantasy and can endure first several episodes, which are considered weak overall.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="180200">I wish they`d produce the rest of the novels... Great series, yet without an ending.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="548590">Of historical settings, fantasy, and the Far East.

It is the one of the only series I have watched more than three complete times, Trigun being the other.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="271155">incredible</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="406803">Epic stories &amp; beautiful music.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="284037">yeah, such a great anime. It`s a pity they didn`t animate the rest of the novel. If the studio couldn`t finish it, they should`ve stop at episode 39, rather than 45. you`ll understand why when you watch the whole series</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="13774">Great story - especially "Shadow of the Moon" and "A Great Distance in The Windę 
But you must see all episodes to understand it well.
Nr1 Anime that I seen till now. And I saw a lot of them by now :)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="147722">great fantasy anime</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="367836">Fantasy as it should be.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="303972">if you can get past episode 20, i guarantee you will love it.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="214037">This must be the best anime out there ever! It has action and politics in a fantasy-setting world and the character development is just breathless.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="204848">:)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="177218">It`s a little slow pacing but overall and interesting anime to watch ~</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="560633">First I must say i really liked this anime and I recommend it. 

The only things that I did not like was the 3 recaps and that many episodes has a loong intro about what has happened so far. 

This anime does not only have one story in it but many short side stories about the different characters. (like 300 years ago this happened (3 episode adventure or meanwhile "charactername" is doing 1-7 ep on that).  

The last episode is a another recap... which makes it ~6 min episode at the end.

The world and characters portrayed in it are very good and it is a good story.

If you got the time check it out.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="282954">The beginning starts out like most would expect. I say give it some time before judging it. There will be an information dump, but don`t worry about it, flashback episodes are really more like a lets review and break down all the world building we dumped on you back there. 

If you like fantasy you may like all the world building and character growth on the protagonist part.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="575342">If you are a fan of fantasy worlds watch it. If you aren`t still watch it. Detailed fantasy adventure. It`s better than Berserk atleast for me.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="167028">Starts off slow, but develops very well.  Unfortunate decision by production to leave out some story from the source materials made it difficult for the later stories to be animated, hence a lack of ending.  Nevertheless, definitely a must see~</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="40254">Still one of the best. Interesting characters, compelling story, action, romance, fantasy - it has it all!
Just watch it and be drawn into another fascinating world.
Perfect 10/10.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="411532">Holy crap!  This anime is one of the best animes I have ever seen.  

The main character is really annoying for about 6 episodes; however, stick with the anime as you won`t be disappointed.  The plot is solid, the artstyle is awesome, the character development is extremely good.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="290165">It is just brilliant work. the best in the fantasy genre. Watched it 4 times and I am going to watch it more. I even read the corresponding translated chapters from the novels. Don`t you dare miss it ;)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="335602">This anime has possibly the best storytelling I have ever seen in anime. Set in an alternate universe, the detail in which the norms and ways of this world are explained, aswell as the character development, are astounding. You get sucked into it, live with and grow to understand the characters, and eagerly await the next action they are going to take. It`s a shame they didn`t animate all 11 novels, but this is definitely a must see for any anime fan, though it`s often overlooked.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="269894">BEST fantasy setting and story that I`ve seen to date. Don`t be put off by the character`s initial reactions. The awkward beginning eventually develops into a captivating tale.

I also recommend the original author`s other works as well - Shiki and Ghost Hunt.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="31156">I`ve been watching anime since the 90`s, and this is still on my top 10 list.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="101924">My all time favorites. A must see anime. Even though at the beginning the show looks like a flop, the main character start to grow and becomes a great character (goes from a crying indecisive schoolgirl to a character to a a powerful and likable character). The secondary cast is top notch (Rakushun and Shouryuu are great), the plot is good (not ground breaking, but solid), the animation is still acceptable and sound is great. You cannot go wrong picking this anime over any other to watch, definitely a must see anime.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="147092">Great plotline and character development.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="691547">One of the best fantasy series
although it`s a bit slow in the begging 
it turns out to be a complex story 
with great attention to details
and also to politics
which was new to me</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="71577">The only thing I can recommend here is not to postpone watching this as stupid me did. I`ve had my eyes on this series for a long time, but I thought it was too long and couldn`t get a good copy of it, etc. and I was just postponing it for years. Then I finally did watch it and I`m banging my head to the wall since. It was too short!!! Seriously, awesome story, incredible storytelling, fantastic atmosphere and some unbelievably well-made character development. Kinda addicting, too. To put it very mildly, it would be a shame to miss out on this one.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="276267">A classic...</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="296475">A truly epic story, it got me totally hooked; superb character development. An absolute must see, IMO.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="53642">Best Fantasy/Parallel-World Anime I`ve seen so far</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="290120">Pseudo-Mythological  Fantasy at its absolute best.  This series is mesmerizing, and I love the character growth, particularly Youko`s.  Features a varied enough cast of characters to fit anyone`s taste, yet they are still genuine in action &amp; emotion. A Well Developed anime, with intricate storylines and character motivations.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="460726">Without a doubt one of the best animes ever made, it`s just a must see! The storyline, animation, landscape and character design is all top-notch, and when all this things come together they made one of the best anime ever.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="263947">Awsome storytelling but sadly it ends prematurely.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="520981">This series is so good that when it ends at episode 45 you`ll find yourself wishing for more.The story and characters really suck you in.The fantasy world created by the writer is capable of much more exploration via this anime. The plot has many other directions it can go in. Even though the series ended at 45 episodes, I know a lot of us 12 Kingdoms fans would be really happy if they made another 45 episodes as there is still a ton of unused potential - including all the other "unexplored" kingdoms, not to mention the rest of the black kirin story.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="28349">Loved how the story evolved with the head character.

Great Series</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="404463">Awesome series and an must seen no matter the type of anime you prefer, in other hand despite the depth of the story line there are whole episodes that flash back what happened in previous episodes also much to my chagrin the series came to an inglorious end. Despite that, i highly recommended it</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="206351">This is a great fantasy series with lots of good, deep, dynamic characters. There is a lot of political intrigue. The ugly side of humanity is often on display, but it makes it so that when the characters finally redeem themselves, it is all the more triumphant.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="281436">One of the best anime i have seen to date. Takes a little to get into it but once your in you can`t get enough and not only that the character building is amazing and well done. The biggest flaw is its un-finished and makes you angry where it leaves you.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="439175">Everything in this show was done the right way.
Any anime fans should see this.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="559673">together with berserk the best dark fantasy anime! you must not skip this one, you ll regret it</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="533361">All four light novel tales that are told in Juuni Kokuki flow together flawlessly. The characters are developed well. The story is sublime. The world that the author creates is well thought out and interesting. The anime is one that can be watched over and over.</recommendation>
</recommendations>
<url>http://www.12kokuki.com/</url>
<creators>
<name id="1050" type="Work">NHK</name>
<name id="3329" type="Music">Ryou Kunihiko</name>
<name id="724" type="Animation Work">Studio Pierrot</name>
<name id="6215" type="Character Design">Tanaka Hiroto</name>
<name id="5716" type="Character Design">Kusumoto Yuuko</name>
<name id="1214" type="Original Work">Ono Fuyumi</name>
<name id="5348" type="Direction">Kobayashi Tsuneo</name>
</creators>
<description>http://anidb.net/ch44 [Nakajima Youko] is class president and an honour student. At home, she is a good daughter, always obedient to her parents. She pleases everyone around her to the extent of ignoring herself due to her lack of confidence. She has nightmares daily and a unique hair colour that cause some friction at home and suspicion at school.
On a day like any other at school, a strange man named http://anidb.net/ch4946 [Keiki] appears before her. He kneels and swears allegiance to her, promising to protect her and never leave her side. Thereafter they are pursued and attacked by demon-like beasts. In this mix enters two of her classmates who unfortunately happen to be at the wrong place at the wrong time. To escape the onslaught, Keiki transports them to his world. Unfortunately during the journey they are ambushed and end up separated from one another.
Now they have to learn how to survive in a new land, one with magic, swords, demon-like beasts and immortals.
This anime is based on text novels written by http://anidb.net/cr1214 [Ono Fuyumi]. It features a complex fantasy world with a rich mythology behind it. The series tells us not only Nakajima Youko`s story, but also stories about other people who came to live in this world.</description>
<ratings>
<permanent count="8234">8.26</permanent>
<temporary count="8425">8.53</temporary>
<review count="27">8.35</review>
</ratings>
<picture>4993.jpg</picture>
<resources>
<resource type="1">
<externalentity>
<identifier>840</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="2">
<externalentity>
<identifier>153</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="3">
<externalentity>
<identifier>880</identifier>
<identifier>rmksij</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="4">
<externalentity>
<url>http://www3.nhk.or.jp/anime/12kokuki/</url>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="6">
<externalentity>
<identifier>The_Twelve_Kingdoms</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="7">
<externalentity>
<identifier>十二国記</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="9">
<externalentity>
<identifier>238148</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="10">
<externalentity>
<identifier>5356</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="15">
<externalentity>
<identifier>2002/12kokuki</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
<tags>
<tag id="7" parentid="2608" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-11-18">
<name>juujin</name>
<description>Kemono, "beast", is a genre of Japanese art and character design that prominently features anthropomorphic animal characters. It is used widely in visual arts, especially drawing and painting, and can be found in many manga, anime, and video game. Anthropomorphic animal characters in the kemono genre are frequently called juujin, "therianthrope"; the kanji for juujin are also sometimes pronounced kemonobito, "beast-human". While their design differs from artist to artist, they generally employ animal traits considered cute and endearing; most kemono characters retain a fundamentally human personality, however, seldom behaving as the actual animals from which they have been anthropomorphized, and as such they are typically depicted living as humans do.
Source: Manga Wikia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>meta tags</name>
<description>These tags are used for maintenance.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="36" parentid="2607" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-04-17">
<name>military</name>
<description>The military, also known as the armed forces, are forces authorized and legally entitled to use deadly force so as to support the interests of the state and its citizens. The task of the military is usually defined as defence of the state and its citizens and the prosecution of war against foreign powers. The military may also have additional functions within a society, including construction, emergency services, social ceremonies, and guarding critical areas.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="308" parentid="2611" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-04-17">
<name>detective</name>
<description>A detective is an investigator, generally either a member of a law enforcement agency or as an individual working in the capacity of private investigators, tasked with solving crimes and other mysteries, such as disappearances, by examining and evaluating clues and records in order to solve the mystery; for a crime, this would mean uncovering the criminal`s identity and/or whereabouts. In some police systems, a detective position is achieved by passing a written test after a person completes the requirements for being a police officer; in others, detectives are college graduates who join directly from civilian life without first serving as uniformed officers.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1365" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2015-02-03">
<name>sentient weapon</name>
<description>A sentient weapon is a common plot device in many works of fantasy and mythology, and is related to the classic motif of the magic sword. Sentient weapons may be human, robotic, or magical (as is the case with any non-technological weapons, such as a sword), but not all magic weapons are sentient. A sentient weapon may experience a moral conflict from its specific nature as a weapon, or may function as the villain, which, through its intelligence, is able to gain power. Another possibility is that it assists the wielder, or is merely neutral.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1396" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-01">
<name>immortality</name>
<description>Immortality is the ability to live in a physical or spiritual form for an infinite or inconceivably vast length of time. Humans, whose life span is limited and who die of age, disease and external trauma, have long sought ways to extend their lives; the Epic of Gilgamesh, considered one of the first great literary works created by mankind, is primarily the quest of a hero seeking to become immortal. The advances of science, in particular medicine and engineering, and especially in the last few centuries, have helped people extend their life span and may yet continue finding ways to do so.
In fiction, immortals are not quite as uncommon as in real life, and the possible implications of endless or very long lives are often explored. Such implications include, but are not limited to: repeatedly accompanying the deaths of those dear to them; having to hide their condition from the mortals surrounding them; becoming disillusioned with their lives and being unable to kill themselves; and even staying forever trapped in the body of a specific physical age, that body most often being that of a child. As such, while many may wish for immortality, it may be little more than a curse for the few who have it.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1637" parentid="2565" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-13">
<name>reverse trap</name>
<description>A female character often mistaken as a male by other characters and/or the viewer due to her masculine appearance, behaviour, and/or language (regardless of her intention).
The reverse case is known as a http://anidb.net/t618 [trap].</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1760" parentid="2608" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-05-23">
<name>bishounen</name>
<description>Young man whose beauty (and sexual appeal) transcends the boundary of gender or sexual orientation.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1802" parentid="2606" infobox="true" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-01-24">
<name>seinen</name>
<description>Seinen, literally "young man", is one of the main demographic classifications applied to manga, and, by extension, to anime, especially manga-based ones. As the name implies, seinen works are marketed primarily to an audience of young men; the age range commonly understood to be the target of such works goes roughly from 17 to somewhere in the 40s.</description>
<picurl>181651.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2094" parentid="2849" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-10-25">
<name>magic</name>
<description>Magic is the art of purportedly manipulating aspects of reality either by supernatural means or through knowledge of unknown occult laws.</description>
<picurl>178878.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2282" parentid="2841" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-11-16">
<name>martial arts</name>
<description>Various sports or skills, mainly of Japanese origin, that originated as forms of self-defense or attack, such as judo, karate, and kendo.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2565" parentid="2608" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-04-14">
<name>cross-dressing</name>
<description>This character sometimes wears clothes traditionally worn by and associated with the opposite sex.
Cross-dressers often hide their cross-dressing identity for a long period of time and thus tend to become adept in accurately portraying the opposite sex in terms of voice, movement, behaviour, temperament, etc.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2604" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-04-02">
<name>content indicators</name>
<description>The content indicators branch is intended to be a less geographically specific tool than the `age rating` used by convention, for warning about things that might cause offence. Obviously there is still a degree of subjectivity involved, but hopefully it will prove useful for parents with delicate children, or children with delicate parents.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-28">
<name>dynamic</name>
<description>Some of the central structural elements in anime are: 
Plot Continuity 
How does the plot or several plots unfold. Are they a strictly linear retelling of one big continuing story, a serial, possibly with several side stories, or is the content chopped into a set of unconnected episodes, only sharing the same setting and characters?
Stereotype Characters
Then there is the question of the character set presentation. Is it completely original, or is it your usual stereotypical character cast. Both choices have their merit, for example it would not really make much sense to reinvent the wheel for a harem anime. Fans of that genre come to expect their favourite stereotype protagonists.
Plot Twists
Finally there is the question of how complex the plot / the story unfolds. Are there side-plots that merge into the main plot leading to unexpected plot twists, or is the anime quite predictable? The latter would not be appropriate for detective stories. In harem anime on the other hand a foreseeable outcome is actually something the fans will come to expect.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2606" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-18">
<name>target audience</name>
<description>Anime, like everything else in the modern world, is targeted towards specific audiences, both implicitly by the creators and overtly by the marketing. While categories are associated with specific sex and age groups, this is not a bar on the anime being enjoyed by people who don`t fit into that band; not only do crossover titles exist, but the categories also have a considerable following outside their main demographic, and a person might as well enjoy anime from all categories. Still, does not invalidate the usefulness of marking a title as one of the categories; the same themes will likely be treated differently in anime geared for different audiences. Only one should not jump the gun and assume that a title will be more or less serious or present content in this or that way due to its target audience, or conversely assume the target audience on the content and its presentation alone. As such, the audience categories help form a broad impression of how a title might work with the announced themes, but offer little to no in-depth information about specific content or its treatment.
The audience categories originate from manga magazines, which group titles of a same intended audience into a magazine that is advertised as belonging to that category, and so manga-based anime will have the category from their parent work. As for anime based on other works, the audience is often debatable, but comparing information such as time slot to the manga-based anime generally helps figure out the most likely possibility.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-29">
<name>themes</name>
<description>Themes describe the very central elements important to the anime stories. They set the backdrop against which the protagonists must face their challenges. Be it School Life, present Daily Life, Military action, Cyberpunk, Law and Order detective work, Sports, or the Underworld. These are only but a few of the more typical backgrounds for anime plots. Add to that a Conspiracy setting with a possible tragic outcome, the Themes span most of the imaginable subject matter relevant to anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2608" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-12-04">
<name>fetishes</name>
<description>Everything under fetishes (except for Bishounen and Juujin) is strictly only meant for hentai (18 Restricted) and ecchi anime. In case of ecchi, it must be the main element of the show and not when there`s only some of it, for example, there`s some ecchi in Shinseiki Evangelion, but the fact you get to see Asuka`s pantsu doesn`t warrant it the schoolgirl fetish category. So be careful to which ecchi show you add fetishes; it`s fairly straightforward with hentai, though. Overall, this category tree is to satisfy the needs of people with different fetishes, so they can search for what tingles their tangle; hence why this is restricted to hentai and full ecchi shows. </description>
</tag>
<tag id="2609" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-22">
<name>original work</name>
<description>What the anime is based on! Mostly of academic interest, but a useful bit of info, hinting at the possible depth of story.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-22">
<name>setting</name>
<description>The setting describes in what time and place an anime takes place. To a certain extent it describes what you can expect from the world in the anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-08">
<name>elements</name>
<description>Next to Themes setting the backdrop for the protagonists in anime, there are the more detailed plot Elements that centre on character interactions: "What do characters do to each other or what is done to them?". Is it violent Action, an awe-inspiring Adventure in a foreign place, the gripping life of a Detective, a slapstick Comedy, an Ecchi Harem anime, a SciFi epic, or some Fantasy travelling adventure?</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2612" parentid="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>time</name>
<description>This placeholder lists different epochs in human history and more vague but important timelines such as the future, the present and the past.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2613" parentid="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>place</name>
<description>The places the anime can take place in. Includes more specific places such as a country on Earth, as well as more general places such as a dystopia or a mirror world.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2622" parentid="2841" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-03">
<name>swordplay</name>
<description>The act or art of using a sword or similar weapon skillfully.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2624" parentid="2612" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-02-20">
<name>present</name>
<description>Somewhere between past and future.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2625" parentid="2612" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-15">
<name>past</name>
<description>Anime that takes place in the past or clearly seems to take place in the past in case of an alternative universe. This category should almost always go together with one of its sub-categories, because the past can either be a depiction of a historical event(s) or not, in which case it would be alternative past.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2628" parentid="6557" weight="500" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-12-17">
<name>fantasy world</name>
<description>A fantasy world is a type of imaginary world, part of a fictional universe. Typical worlds involve, but are not limited to magic or magical abilities and a medieval theme. Some examples include: a parallel world tenuously connected to Earth via magical portals or items; a fictional Earth-like planet in the remote past or future; or an entirely independent world set in another universe. Many fantasy worlds draw heavily on real world history, geography and sociology, and also on folklore.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2630" parentid="2613" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-13">
<name>Earth</name>
<description>The Earth is the third planet from the Sun, and the densest and fifth-largest of the eight planets in the Solar System. It is in effect a ball of hot mud, but on the surface it`s cold enough, so most of us live on it (or are supposed to). It is circa 4.5 billion years old, and, unless we humans succeed in destroying it over the next couple of centuries, it is expected to last for quite another while, though the changes in the Sun`s emissions due to its aging will likely cause the extinction of everything; the species of earthlings are guaranteed to die, even if we fail to kill them -- unless, of course, we find ourselves another planet and figure out a way to take everything there. Our little planet on a corner of this galaxy may mean nothing in the grand scheme of things, but to its inhabitants it is their home, so, as a species, we cherish it dearly, to the point many cultures even to this day deify it. Being the home to the human civilizations, the Earth is the main setting of most fiction, be it anime or otherwise, but not only are many titles set in other places, such as unrelated fantasy worlds, in a considerable number of fictional titles the Earth is actually destroyed by aggressive alien invaders.</description>
<picurl>126792.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2647" parentid="2849" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-03">
<name>high fantasy</name>
<description>Generally a serious and epic story set in an invented world. The world may be more or less based on real world environments or history. Typical fantastical elements are usually dominating, such as elves, dwarves, magicians, invented languages, quests; just to name a few.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2648" parentid="2849" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-11-04">
<name>contemporary fantasy</name>
<description>Contemporary fantasy, also known as modern fantasy or indigenous fantasy, is a sub-genre of fantasy, set in the present day. It is perhaps most popular for its sub-genre, urban fantasy.
These terms are used to describe stories set in the putative real world (often referred to as consensus reality) in contemporary times, in which magic and magical creatures exist, either living in the interstices of our world or leaking over from alternate worlds. It thus has much in common with, and sometimes overlaps with secret history; a work of fantasy in which the magic could not remain secret or does not have any known relationship to known history would not fit into this subgenre. Occasionally certain contemporary fantasy novels will make reference to pop culture.
Novels in which modern characters travel into alternate worlds, and all the magical action takes place there (except for the portal required to transport them), are not considered contemporary fantasy. Thus, C.S. Lewis`s The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe, where all fantasy events take place in the land of Narnia which is reached via a magic wardrobe, would not count as contemporary fantasy; on the other hand, the part of The Magician`s Nephew, where the Empress Jadis gets to London, tries to take over the Earth and clashes with police and a crowd of cockneys, would qualify as such.
Contemporary fantasy is also to be distinguished from horror fiction, which also often has contemporary settings. When encountering magical events and creatures, the protagonist of a horror novel is horrified, while the protagonist of a fantasy novel (contemporary or otherwise) is filled with a sense of joy and wonder. Horrifying events may happen, but the fundamental distinction is vital.
In his preface to That Hideous Strength, one of the earlier works falling within this sub-genre, C.S. Lewis explained why, when writing a tale about "magicians, devils, pantomime animals and planetary angels", he chose to start it with a detailed depiction of narrow-minded academic politics at a provincial English university and the schemes of crooked real estate developers: "I am following the traditional fairy-tale. We do not always notice its method, because the cottages, castles, woodcutters and petty kings with which a fairy tale opens have become for us as remote as the witches and ogres to which it proceeds. But they were not remote at all to the men who first made and enjoyed the tales". The same is true for many of the later works in the genre, which often begin with a seemingly normal scene of modern daily life to then disclose supernatural and magical beings and events hidden behind the scenes.
Source: wiki</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2649" parentid="2849" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-03">
<name>dark fantasy</name>
<description>Focus set on darker themes in a fantasy setting, sometimes leaning towards horror elements. Bleak and pessimistic tones often dominate. Dark supernatural beings like vampires may play a significant role.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2672" parentid="2834" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-05-31">
<name>Japan</name>
<description>Last stronghold for humanity. If Tokyo falls, it`s all over. Tokyo Tower will undoubtedly fall anyway.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2749" parentid="2604" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2005-05-07">
<name>nudity</name>
<description>Nudity is the state of wearing no clothing. The wearing of clothing is exclusively a human characteristic. The amount of clothing worn depends on functional considerations (such as a need for warmth or protection from the elements) and social considerations. In some situations the minimum amount of clothing (i.e. covering of a person`s genitals) may be socially acceptable, while in others much more clothing is expected.
People, as individuals and in groups, have varying attitudes towards their own nudity. Some people are relaxed about appearing less than fully clothed in front of others, while others are uncomfortable or inhibited in that regard. People are nude in a variety of situations, and whether they are prepared to disrobe in front of others depends on the social context in which the issue arises. For example, people need to bathe without clothing, some people also sleep in the nude, some prefer to sunbathe in the nude or at least topless, while others are nude in other situations. Some people adopt naturism as a lifestyle.
Though the wearing of clothes is the social norm in most cultures, some cultures, groups and individuals are more relaxed about nudity, though attitudes often depend on context. On the other hand, some people feel uncomfortable in the presence of any nudity, and the presence of a nude person in a public place can give rise to controversy, irrespective of the attitude of the person who is nude. Besides meeting social disapproval, in some places public nudity may constitute a crime of indecent exposure. Many people have strong views on nudity, which to them can involve issues and standards of modesty, decency and morality. Some people have an psychological aversion to nudity, called gymnophobia. Many people regard nudity to be inherently sexual and erotic.
Nudity is to be found in a multitude of media, including art, photography, film and on the Internet. It is a factor in adult entertainment of various types.
Especially gratuitous fanservice anime shows tend to show their (usually female) characters frequently without any clothes, though often hiding genitals through the means of additions like steam.
Source: wiki</description>
<picurl>60576.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2750" parentid="2604" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-07-28">
<name>violence</name>
<description>Physical force against self or other, compelling action against one`s will on pain of being hurt.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2772" parentid="36" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>feudal warfare</name>
<description>Feudal Warfare is the warfare of the Middle Ages and therefore the setting must take place in a time line similar to that of Middle Ages or its Asian/American counterparts, or in a fantasy world. Generally it can be described the same way as the Military category, just that the weapons used are swords, spears, bows, catapults, cannons and other weapons used in the Middle Ages.
Note: Just because the anime contains a guy or a couple of guys with swords wondering about, doesn`t make it applicable for this category, unless there are larger military organizations/groups involved in armed conflict with each other, you might not want to add this genre.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2790" parentid="2605" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-01-17">
<name>plot continuity</name>
<description>Consistency of the characteristics of persons, plot, objects, places and events seen by the viewer.
A single linear focused plot is highly continuous.
A truly random plot is highly discontinuous.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2793" parentid="2883" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-07">
<name>performance</name>
<description>The song performance on stage or acting in a theatre is a central part of the character`s life in this anime type.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2799" parentid="2609" infobox="true" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-05-14">
<name>novel</name>
<description>Note that novel means book with words in paper, so no comics and no "visual novels", which should go under manga and dating-sim - visual Novel/erotic game respectively.
Note that it can be applied to novels as we know them but also the typical light novels for teens and young adults, which are common in Japan and aside from being short include a number of illustrations.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2834" parentid="2630" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-10-04">
<name>Asia</name>
<description>Asia is Earth`s largest and most populous continent, located primarily in the eastern and northern hemispheres and sharing the continental landmass of Eurasia with the continent of Europe. Asia covers an area of 44,579,000 square kilometers, about 30% of Earth`s total land area and 8.7% of the Earth`s total surface area. The continent, which has long been home to the majority of the human population, was the site of many of the first civilizations. Asia is notable for not only its overall large size and population, but also dense and large settlements as well as vast barely populated regions within the continent of 4.4 billion people.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
<picurl>192245.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2838" parentid="6557" infobox="true" weight="500" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-12-20">
<name>parallel universe</name>
<description>Parallel universe/world or alternative reality is a self-contained separate reality coexisting with our own. Because "alternative reality" sometimes implies that the reality is a variant of our own, like for example a mirror world, we`ll use the term "Parallel Universe" which is more general, without any connotations implying a relationship (or lack thereof) with our own universe (meaning a fantasy world can just as well have an alternative reality, doesn`t need to be our reality). To put it more simply, this category is to show if more than 1 universe/reality/world is present in the anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2841" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-09-08">
<name>action</name>
<description>Action anime usually involve a fairly straightforward story of good guys versus bad guys, where most disputes are resolved by using physical force. It often contains a lot of shooting, explosions and fighting.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2844" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-05-07">
<name>angst</name>
<description>A feeling of general discomfort and uneasiness is present due to either trivial or more serious reasons, often accompanied by depression.
Warning: may contain copious amounts of brooding and sighing.
Etymology: "Angst" is a German word meaning fear or anxiety.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2849" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2005-05-07">
<name>fantasy</name>
<description>Fantasy is a genre of fiction that uses magic and other supernatural phenomena as a primary element of plot, theme, or setting. Many works within the genre take place in fictional worlds where magic is common. Fantasy is generally distinguished from science fiction and horror by the expectation that it steers clear of (pseudo-)scientific and macabre themes, respectively, though there is a great deal of overlap between the three (which are subgenres of speculative fiction).
In popular culture, the genre of fantasy is dominated by its medievalist form, especially since the worldwide success of The Lord of the Rings books by J. R. R. Tolkien. In its broadest sense however, fantasy comprises works by many writers, artists, filmmakers, and musicians, from ancient myths and legends to many recent works embraced by a wide audience today.
Fantasy is a vibrant area of academic study in a number of disciplines (English, cultural studies, comparative literature, history, medieval studies). Work in this area ranges widely, from the structuralist theory of Tzvetan Todorov, which emphasizes the fantastic as a liminal space, to work on the connections (political, historical, literary) between medievalism and popular culture
Source: Wiki</description>
<picurl>68768.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2850" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-10-25">
<name>adventure</name>
<description>Adventures are exciting stories, with new experiences or exotic locales. Adventures are designed to provide an action-filled, energetic experience for the viewer. Rather than the predominant emphasis on violence and fighting that is found in pure action anime, however, the viewer of adventures can live vicariously through the travels, conquests, explorations, creation of empires, struggles and situations that confront the main characters, actual historical figures or protagonists. Under the category of adventures, we can include traditional swashbucklers, serialized films, and historical spectacles, searches or expeditions for lost continents, "jungle" and "desert" epics, treasure hunts and quests, disaster films, and heroic journeys or searches for the unknown. Adventure films are often, but not always, set in an historical period, and may include adapted stories of historical or literary adventure heroes, kings, battles, rebellion, or piracy.</description>
<picurl>178879.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2851" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-15">
<name>horror</name>
<description>The horror cinematic genre is characterized by the attempt to make the viewer experience dread, fear, terror, or horror. Often their plots involve the intrusion of an evil force, event or personage, sometimes of supernatural origin, on the mundane world and the consequences thereof.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2857" parentid="2611" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>anthropomorphism</name>
<description>Anthropomorphism is the attribution of uniquely human characteristics to non-human beings, inanimate objects, or natural or supernatural phenomena. If it`s an animal or an object (AI excluded) and it speaks and/or does other human-like things (dresses up) then we`re dealing with anthropomorphism.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2864" parentid="2607" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-12-29">
<name>daily life</name>
<description>The antics of the protagonists do not take place in some exotic setting or time, but in everyday life. When not "at the job" this means getting up in the morning, making meals, house cleaning, going shopping or out to eat, visiting the bath house or spa, leisure activities in the spare time, etc. The time "on the job" for students is School Life, for others working in their profession. Daily Life is basically a synonym for everything normal, repetitive, and trivial happening to your average person.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2867" parentid="2607" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-08">
<name>politics</name>
<description>From commies to fat capitalist pigs, all the stuff done by the "guys with the power", mainly evil tactics for gaining more power over the masses.
Watching this title may remind you why CNN is boring.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2874" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-16">
<name>disaster</name>
<description>A disaster is a large-scale natural or human-made situation that causes great loss of or threat to life, health, property, or environment in such a way that society or environment are affected substantially.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2883" parentid="2607" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-07">
<name>the arts</name>
<description>The arts represent an outlet of human expression, usually influenced by culture, and driven by human creative impulse. Major constituents of the arts include literature – including poetry, novels and short stories, and epics; performing arts – among them music, dance, and theatre; culinary arts such as baking, chocolatiering, and winemaking; media arts like photography and film, and visual arts – including drawing, painting, and sculpting. Some art forms combine a visual element with performance (e.g. film) and the written word (e.g. comics).
From prehistoric cave paintings to modern day films, art serves as a vessel for storytelling and conveying mankind`s relationship with its environment.
Source: Wiki</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2887" parentid="2611" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-16">
<name>tragedy</name>
<description>Tragedy is a form of drama characterized by seriousness and dignity, usually involving a conflict between a character and some higher power, such as the law, the gods, fate, or society.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2888" parentid="2607" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-16">
<name>coming of age</name>
<description>In the strict sense the Coming of age describes a young person`s transition from adolescence to adulthood. In anime the term is used in a more general sense where the protagonists have to face a challenge, make an important decision in their life, take on responsibility, or learn a lesson, and by overcoming these obstacles they reach a higher level of maturity.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-12-04">
<name>unsorted</name>
<description>a bunch of tags that still need to be either deleted or moved into proper places.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3092" parentid="6233" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-03-02">
<name>important haircut</name>
<description>When a character cuts off his or her hair, it often symbolizes a rite of passage or bout of character growth. A princess striking out on an adventure, or a new recruit at boot camp, for instance. Hair is something that takes time and effort to grow, so parting with it voluntarily can be a powerful act.
This is particularly a big deal when women get haircuts. Yet in fiction, even an accidental hair slicing can leave a character with a surprisingly even cut.
In many religions (Western Christianity, Ancient Egyptian religion, and others) priests and/or monks cut/shave their hair. Roman Catholic nuns also tend to cut and mantain their hair short under their veils when they enter the nunneries. The cutting of one`s own hair is also a part of Buddhist mythology, specifically something done by Siddhartha himself early on in his path to enlightenment, so anime examples might draw from this as an allusion. There are also some cultures, including Native American and many Asians, where a person would cut his or her hair as an act of grief, disgrace, or even rebellion. In the Confucian tradition, hair (like the rest of your body) is considered a gift from your parents and may not be damaged without a very good reason. Furthermore, prisoners and psychiatric patients commonly have their heads shaved, often to prevent the spread of lice, but sometimes also as a demeaning measure.
Source: TVTRope</description>
<picurl>169641.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="3123" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-06-27">
<name>symbiotic creatures</name>
<description>Some creatures form symbiotic relationships with humans in this anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3148" parentid="6247" weight="0" localspoiler="true" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-10-14">
<name>open-ended</name>
<description>The ending of this anime is left to the viewers imagination. There are no clear hints at a definite story outcome, just several possibilities are presented.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3285" parentid="2850" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true">
<name>journey</name>
</tag>
<tag id="3314" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-05-10">
<name>fate</name>
<description>Fate — The predestined path of all things. The outcome is inevitable and the consequences predetermined. Whether or not the protagonist ultimately decides to follow this path shall weigh heavily on their soul.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3326" parentid="6232" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-03-20">
<name>very high jumps</name>
<description>For some reason or other, e.g. like having superpowers, the characters in this anime have the ability to jump up unnaturally high distances.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3435" parentid="2851" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-17">
<name>eating of humans</name>
<description>The eating of humans, also called man-eating, is the practice of some species to prey on human beings for nourishment. Examples of possible hunters may include Earth animals, alien species, zombies or other undead, and so forth. Eating of humans is not to be confused with http://anidb.net/t3815 [human cannibalism]; the former is about other species eating people, while the latter is about humans eating fellow humans.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3472" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-06-29">
<name>unusual illness</name>
<description>A character has unusual or unlikely side-effects from an accident or suffers symptoms from ailments that could only exist within the anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3600" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-03-22">
<name>thought-provoking</name>
<description>The usually relatively quiet way the story in this anime is being told, gives the viewer the chance to not only follow the story but also to think about it.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3663" parentid="6347" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-11-14">
<name>body takeover</name>
<description>A person`s body is taken over by some foreign intelligence. It`s not brainwashing, because they still have control of their own mind — but that`s all they have. Either they`ve been reduced to a spectator in their own body, or their soul has been booted out of their body entirely. Either way, the rest of the cast will soon find he`s not himself.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3809" parentid="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-05-24">
<name>character driven</name>
<description>The main appeal of the show is the way the characters are portrayed and interact, focusing on dialogue, spending time together or getting to know each other. These anime are not "story-less" but story is secondary to character development and the characters themselves and what they experience.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3826" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2011-04-26">
<name>evil laugh</name>
<description>The thing all great evil villains do after saying/doing something evil.
Some notable examples of great evil villains with evil laughs: Dr. Evil, Dr. Horrible, The Joker, Lelouche, Light, and Mickey Mouse.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3836" parentid="3314" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-06-04">
<name>the chosen one!</name>
<description>One of the characters in the anime is the "chosen one", the one to bring about change, the only one to "set things right" in a "good" ending, or bring about complete destruction in a "bad" ending.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3958" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="true" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-23">
<name>coup d`etat</name>
<description>A coup d`état (/ˌkuːdeɪˈtɑː/; French: blow of state; plural: coups d`état), also known as a coup, a putsch, or an overthrow, is the sudden and illegal seizure of a government, usually instigated by a small group of the existing state establishment to depose the established government and replace it with a new ruling body. A coup d`état is considered successful when the usurpers establish their dominance. If a coup fails, a civil war may ensue.</description>
<picurl>10266.jpeg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="4022" parentid="6230" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-11-29">
<name>strong female lead</name>
<description>The lead female character has a strong personality and plays a part that is not the typical damsel-in-distress role. 
This is the exact opposite of the “damsel in distress” tag.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4057" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-02-19">
<name>magical creatures</name>
<description>Magical creatures are beings associated with a fantasy setting, thus do not exist in reality. Apparently they were "created of" or "powered by" magic. An incantation may have brought them into existence.
Examples: A legendary creature, a mythological or folkloric creature, a fairy or demon, ...</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4128" parentid="6233" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2008-07-29">
<name>zero to hero</name>
<description>With his first appearance, this character is getting his ass kicked by nearly everyone, but as the plot continues, through training (mental or physical) or instant power-up, he changes into a killing/fighting/winning machine.
The best example: Makunouchi Ippo from Hajime no Ippo series.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4203" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2008-06-03">
<name>rebellion</name>
<description>Rebellion, uprising, or insurrection is a refusal of obedience or order. It may, therefore, be seen as encompassing a range of behaviors aimed at destroying or taking over the position of an established authority such as a government, governor, president, political leader, financial institution, or person in charge. On the one hand the forms of behaviour can include non-violent methods such as the (overlapping but not quite identical) phenomena of civil disobedience, civil resistance and nonviolent resistance. On the other hand it may encompass violent campaigns. Those who participate in rebellions, especially if they are armed rebellions, are known as "rebels".&#13;
&#13;
Source: Wiki</description>
<picurl>163803.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="4397" parentid="2867" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-13">
<name>court politics</name>
<description>Court politics are the power struggles internal to the retinue of sovereign rulers, nobles, and other persons of similar social stature, generally in monarchical contexts.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4517" parentid="6233" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-13">
<name>inter-dimensional schoolgirl</name>
<description>One, or more, schoolgirls cross through time, space or some dimension using a space-warp-magic-portal-wormhole-singularity-thing to save one, or more, worlds, or planets.
A major twist could be that the schoolgirl might originate from that very magic-futuristic world, bearing one great secret legendary power to defeat one big bad legendary foe. The return back home is the leitmotiv of the whole series.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5889" parentid="2094" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-03-05">
<name>magic weapons</name>
<description>The characters in this anime wield magic weapons.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5890" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2011-04-10">
<name>medieval</name>
<description>Setting is placed in the so called "dark ages". It can be either European style, oriental style or Chinese/Japanese style of castles, armour, ways of fighting etc.. 
Also the average education is weak, superstition is high and fights are settled on foot or horseback. Furthermore the level to technology is rather low.
Note: The perceived low level of cultural and technological evolution may be offset by an influx of magic (fantasy stories) or very sophisticated technology that the inhabitants choose to make less obvious to the viewer.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6149" parentid="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>TO BE MOVED TO CHARACTER</name>
<description>Tags under this parent tag are going to be moved to character tags and removed from the anime they`re currently assigned to. They will be blocked from the anime system once that move is complete. Please help with that job if you know what characters they should be assigned to.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6230" parentid="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-20">
<name>cast</name>
</tag>
<tag id="6232" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-10-21">
<name>character related tags which need deleting or merging</name>
</tag>
<tag id="6233" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-08-11">
<name>tropes</name>
<description>A trope is a commonly recurring literary and rhetorical devices, motifs or clichés in creative works. This use is a broader redefining of a literary trope, the use of figurative language, via word, phrase, or even an image, for artistic effect, such as using a figure of speech.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6247" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-10-31">
<name>ending tags that need merging</name>
</tag>
<tag id="6332" parentid="2874" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-04">
<name>famine</name>
<description>Widespread scarcity of food caused by various factors, including crop failure, population unbalance and/or government policies.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6347" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-17">
<name>body and host</name>
<description>When a foreign entity like that of a symbiote, body snatcher, puppeteer parasite, or even a hacker (when regarding machines like robots and computers) enters/outright hijacks a body, the possessed subject becomes what is usually called: the host.
The basic purpose of the host varies on what the point was for it to have been hijacked in the first place. Sometimes it`s used as a disguise, other times it`s used as a decoy and destraction, even simply being used as a weapon and piece of armor that the possessor uses to cause sheer chaos and destruction, but sometimes... a host can be used for fetish fuel.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6557" parentid="2613" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-12-20">
<name>fictional world</name>
<description>A fictional world is any world that is clearly not the universe humankind hails from and lives in. This may include completely fictional worlds, computer-generated worlds, parallel worlds accessible through portals, and so on.</description>
</tag>
</tags>
<characters>
<character id="44" type="main character in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="96">8.71</rating>
<name>Nakajima Youko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A sixteen year old honour student in Japan who lives an ordinary life; her primary worry is her naturally red hair. When a man named Keiki suddenly appears at her school, he bows at her feet, swearing loyalty to her and offering protection; when the school is attacked by a giant bird, she reluctantly accepts his oath. He gives her a sword and transports her across the Void Sea to the Twelve Kingdoms, where she ends up in the Kingdom of Kou.
Youko is initially confused by the changes that have been brought onto her, including a complete change in her appearance and being stranded in an unknown land with no means of returning home. As she searches for Keiki, she finds herself constantly battling against demons and being betrayed many times. While Youko becomes wary of trusting others, she eventually comes to befriend and trust a hanjyu named Rakushun. They escape to the Kingdom of En, where Youko learns that she is the heir to the throne of the kingdom of Kei, and although she is initially reluctant, she accepts the position through her growth in the story.</description>
<picture>21227.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="360" picture="171401.jpg">Hisakawa Aya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4944" type="secondary cast in" update="2011-04-07">
<rating votes="21">2.36</rating>
<name>Sugimoto Yuka</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>One of Youko`s classmates in Japan and gets transported to Kou along with Youko and Asano. She enjoys fantasy books and is thrilled to be part of the adventure, believing that she is destined for greatness. Destined to be a rival, she becomes extremely jealous of Youko when she finds out that Youko is the "chosen one" and believes herself to be just as worthy. The king of Kou takes advantage of this to convince her to fight against Youko.</description>
<picture>21184.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1826" picture="171157.jpg">Ishizu Aya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4945" type="secondary cast in" update="2011-04-07">
<rating votes="19">1.64</rating>
<name>Asano Ikuya</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Another one of Youko`s classmates who is transported to the kingdom of Kou. He goes missing after a battle between Yuka and Youko and is not seen by either of them for some time. Asano eventually becomes part of a group of Shusei and works for them as they travelled through the kingdoms.</description>
<picture>21185.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3002" picture="17154.jpg">Ueda Yuuji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4946" type="main character in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="30">4.55</rating>
<name>Keiki</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A kirin and the Saiho of Kei. Like all Kirin, Keiki abhors violence and prefers peaceful resolutions. Keiki appears as a very quiet and unemotional type, however does have caring qualities, especially seen towards the kirin Taiki.</description>
<picture>21186.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="139" picture="29283.jpg">Koyasu Takehito</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4947" type="secondary cast in" update="2011-04-09">
<rating votes="20">8.34</rating>
<name>Shouryuu</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Like Youko, Shoryuu is a taika. He has ruled En for approximately five hundred years and is considered a genius of administration. However, Shoryuu believes that all kings have the potential to be great and that he is by no means exceptional as a human being.
Shouryuu is currently the King of En (En-Ou in the anime, though in TokyoPop`s english translation of the novels he is called the Ever-King). When he travels incognito, he goes by the name of Fuukan. His Japanese name is Komatsu Naotaka.</description>
<picture>21187.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="260" picture="17083.jpg">Aizawa Masaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4948" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="17">6.78</rating>
<name>Rokuta</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>When the kingdom of En chooses to aid Youko to rescue Keiki and free the kingdom of Kei from its false queen, Enki and Rakushun travel through various provinces in Kei to persuade the governors to abandon the imposter. He also plays a part in helping the kirin of Tai. Enki appears as a young boy compared to other kirin like Keiki because he matured at a younger age. He and Shoryuu share a good relationship and are able to treat one another in a casual manner.</description>
<picture>21188.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="254" picture="17073.jpg">Yamaguchi Kappei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4949" type="secondary cast in" update="2012-03-12">
<rating votes="41">8.03</rating>
<name>Rakushun</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A hanjyuu with the form of a rat originally from the Kingdom of Kou. Rakushun is proud of being a hanjyuu and is somewhat uncomfortable in his human form; Youko only learns that he could appear as a human after quite some time. Though Youko is initially distrustful of him, he becomes her first good friend in the Twelve Kingdoms. He is very intelligent and knowledgeable, teaching Youko essential skills on how to live in the Twelve Kingdoms as well as politics and customs.</description>
<picture>21189.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="191" picture="17006.jpg">Suzumura Ken`ichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4950" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="7">3.44</rating>
<name>Aozaru</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The physical manifestation of the sentient spirit of the scabbard of the Suiguutou (the Water Monkey Sword). The sword is a royal treasure to the kingdom of Kei and can only be wielded by the kingdom`s rightful ruler - as such, Youko is the only one who can draw the sword from its sheath. The sword was forged from a water demon that a previous great ruler of Kei had defeated while the scabbard was created from a long-tailed monkey demon. From the scabbard hangs a large jewel that can heal the one who holds it.</description>
<picture>21190.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="389" picture="56097.jpg">Okano Kousuke</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4951" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="4">2.70</rating>
<name>Takasato Kaname</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The kirin of Tai, though is not fully mature and is actually a heina (an immature kirin), and Koki, a rare black kirin. Like Youko, Shouryuu, and Enki, he is a taika from Hourai; as a result, he is known by the name Takasato Kaname.</description>
<picture>21191.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="389" picture="56097.jpg">Okano Kousuke</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4952" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="15">4.13</rating>
<name>Taiki</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The kirin of Tai, though is not fully mature and is actually a heina (an immature kirin), and Koki, a rare black kirin. Like Youko, Shouryuu, and Enki, he is a taika from Hourai; as a result, he is known by the name Takasato Kaname.</description>
<picture>21192.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3" picture="44969.jpg">Kugimiya Rie</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4953" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="15">4.98</rating>
<name>Haku Sanshi</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21193.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1813" picture="172159.jpg">Katsuki Masako</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4954" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="5">4.92</rating>
<name>Youka</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21194.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="15" picture="44976.jpg">Yukana</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4955" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="7">6.94</rating>
<name>Gyousou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A famous general of Tai. After the death of the previous King of Tai, Gyousou ascended Mount Hou in hopes of becoming the new king. Though Taiki is terrified of Gyousou and unsure if he has chosen the right person to become the King of Tai, Taiki eventually realises his fear of Gyousou was how he recognised Gyousou was to become king.</description>
<picture>21195.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="168" picture="80607.jpg">Fujiwara Keiji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4956" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="6">4.49</rating>
<name>Risai</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The general of Tai`s Jou Province and well-known, though she is not as renowned as Gyousou. When Taiki`s return to the Twelve Kingdoms is announced, she is among the many who ascend Mount Hou in hopes of being chosen as the new king. She is a sennin (sage) as a result of becoming a general of Jou since the governor of Jou, who has a lived a long life, requires those who serve him to also possess longevity as well to retain their usefulness. Taiki develops a friendly relationship with her, but in the end does not recognize her as Tai`s new king. After Gyousou ascends the throne of Tai, she remains a loyal subject.</description>
<picture>21196.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="252" picture="149852.jpg">Shindou Naomi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4957" type="secondary cast in" update="2015-07-27">
<rating votes="4">4.84</rating>
<name>Kenrou Shinkun</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Kenrou Shinkun is a heavenly sage tasked with guarding and protecting the people who travel across the Yellow Sea.</description>
<picture>21197.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="194" picture="130580.jpg">Ishida Akira</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4958" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="17">4.34</rating>
<name>Ooki Suzu</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Originally born to a poor farmer`s family in Meiji era Japan, she is swept into the Twelve Kingdoms by a shoku after falling off a cliff when she was sold to pay off her family`s debt. As a kaikyaku, she is unable to communicate with anyone and soon falls into despair.</description>
<picture>21198.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2039" picture="41388.jpg">Wakabayashi Naomi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4959" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="22">7.97</rating>
<name>Shoukei</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The sheltered princess of Hou, until her father`s government was overthrown due to his overly strict enforcement of the law; 600,000 of his people were executed during his reign. When her father is assassinated, her mother and the kirin of Hou are killed before her; Shoukei is spared because she had been unaware of her father`s actions. Her name is removed from the register of Immortals and she is stripped of her royal name; as a commoner, Shoukei can only use her given name, Sonshou. Revoked her of status as member of Hou`s royal family, Shoukei is forced to live anonymously as a peasant without any luxuries and is displeased with the drastic changes in her life.</description>
<picture>21199.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="166" picture="23196.jpg">Kuwashima Houko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4960" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="7">2.73</rating>
<name>Riyou</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21200.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="393" picture="46104.jpg">Takayama Minami</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4961" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="10">6.02</rating>
<name>Kyouou Shushou</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21202.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="321" picture="17158.jpg">Yamazaki Wakana</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4962" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="5">4.83</rating>
<name>Saiou Kouko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21203.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2040" picture="186173.jpg">Suzuki Reiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4963" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="10">4.90</rating>
<name>Enho</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21205.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="289" picture="186204.jpg">Nishimura Tomomichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4964" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="6">3.18</rating>
<name>Seishuu</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21206.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="692" picture="188445.jpg">Hiramatsu Akiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4965" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="5">4.48</rating>
<name>Rangyoku</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21209.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="563" picture="73156.jpg">Kawakami Tomoko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4966" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="3">2.87</rating>
<name>Keikei</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21210.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="540" picture="41046.jpg">Chiba Chiemi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4967" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="3">2.70</rating>
<name>Shoukou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21211.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="382" picture="186900.jpg">Ookawa Tooru</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4968" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="5">3.27</rating>
<name>Gahou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21212.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="42809" picture="188721.jpg">Nakata Kazuhiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4969" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="5">5.74</rating>
<name>Sekki</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21214.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="196" picture="17010.jpg">Nojima Kenji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4970" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="5">5.44</rating>
<name>Koshou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21215.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="292" picture="68967.jpg">Nishi Rintarou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4971" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="11">6.82</rating>
<name>Kantai</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21216.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="455" picture="17356.jpg">Matsumoto Yasunori</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4972" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="7">2.67</rating>
<name>Kouya</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A young boy who was abandoned by his impoverished mother when he was young, Kouya was raised by a youma he called Ookii-no (big one), who called Kouya Chiisai-no (little one). He met Rokuta when they are young and Enki revealed his wish to travel to Hourai, believing that it is a peaceful land and hoping to find his mother. Rokuta named his new friend Kouya, meaning midnight as they had met at midnight. Not wishing to forget his new name, particularly since he had forgotten the name his mother had given him, Kouya asked that Ookii-no call him Kouya and began to call Ookii-no Rokuta in order to remember his new friend.</description>
<picture>21219.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="194" picture="130580.jpg">Ishida Akira</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4973" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="11">2.33</rating>
<name>Atsuyu</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21220.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2041" picture="21380.jpg">Ookura Masaaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4974" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="5">4.65</rating>
<name>Ribi</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21222.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1813" picture="172159.jpg">Katsuki Masako</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="4975" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-03-14">
<rating votes="3">3.91</rating>
<name>Shukou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>21223.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2016" picture="21318.jpg">Yanaka Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="47714" type="appears in" update="2012-08-11">
<rating votes="3">4.05</rating>
<name>Shoushun</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>5647.png</picture>
<seiyuu id="3" picture="44969.jpg">Kugimiya Rie</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="47715" type="appears in" update="2012-08-11">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Seishou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>4601.gif</picture>
<seiyuu id="231" picture="23486.jpg">Madono Mitsuaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="47716" type="appears in" update="2012-08-11">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Mousen</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>92278.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="10143" picture="37459.jpg">Higo Makoto</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="47717" type="appears in" update="2012-08-11">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Itan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>4602.gif</picture>
<seiyuu id="282" picture="17112.jpg">Houki Katsuhisa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="47718" type="appears in" update="2012-08-11">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>In Hakutaku</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>92279.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="409" picture="24867.jpg">Arimoto Kinryuu</seiyuu>
</character>
</characters>
<episodes>
<episode id="157" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">1</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-04-09</airdate>
<rating votes="42">6.12</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 一章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 1</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 1</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Isshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="166" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">2</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-04-16</airdate>
<rating votes="28">6.26</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 二章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 2</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 2</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Ni Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="455" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">3</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-04-23</airdate>
<rating votes="27">6.22</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 三章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 3</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 3</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - San Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="456" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">4</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-04-30</airdate>
<rating votes="24">7.31</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 四章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 4</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 4</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Yon Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="457" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">5</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-05-07</airdate>
<rating votes="26">8.56</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 五章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 5</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 5</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Go Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="1425" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">9</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-06-11</airdate>
<rating votes="18">9.15</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 九章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 9</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 9</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Kyuu Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="1426" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">8</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-06-04</airdate>
<rating votes="17">8.34</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 八章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 8</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 8</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Hachi Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="1427" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">7</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-05-28</airdate>
<rating votes="20">8.33</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 七章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 7</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 7</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Nana Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="1428" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">6</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-05-21</airdate>
<rating votes="24">8.44</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 六章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 6</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 6</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Roku Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="2721" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">11</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-06-25</airdate>
<rating votes="17">9.30</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 十一章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 11</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 11</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Juuisshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="2722" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">10</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-06-18</airdate>
<rating votes="18">8.59</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 十章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 10</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 10</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Juu Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="2731" update="2006-08-06">
<epno type="1">12</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-07-02</airdate>
<rating votes="15">8.77</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 十二章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Chapter 12</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть 12</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Juuni Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="4069" update="2008-07-21">
<epno type="1">13</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-07-09</airdate>
<rating votes="14">9.36</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 終章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Last Chapter</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Часть последняя</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Shuushou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="4634" recap="true" update="2008-07-21">
<epno type="1">14</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-07-16</airdate>
<rating votes="16">4.73</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">月の影 影の海 転章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shadow of the Moon, The Sea of Shadow - Transition Chapter</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Тень Луны, Море Тени. Интерлюдия</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuki no Kage, Kage no Umi - Tenshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="4635" update="2008-07-21">
<epno type="1">15</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-09-03</airdate>
<rating votes="16">8.69</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の海 迷宮の岸 一章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Sea of Wind, The Shore of The Maze - Chapter 1</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Море Ветра, Берег-лабиринт. Часть 1</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Umi, Meikyuu no Kishi - Isshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="4636" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">16</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-09-10</airdate>
<rating votes="14">7.71</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の海 迷宮の岸 二章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Sea of Wind, The Shore of The Maze - Chapter 2</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Море Ветра, Берег-лабиринт. Часть 2</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Umi, Meikyuu no Kishi - Ni Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="5583" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">17</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-09-17</airdate>
<rating votes="15">8.82</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の海 迷宮の岸 三章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Sea of Wind, The Shore of The Maze - Chapter 3</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Море Ветра, Берег-лабиринт. Часть 3</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Umi, Meikyuu no Kishi - San Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="5591" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">18</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-09-24</airdate>
<rating votes="14">8.35</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の海 迷宮の岸 四章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Sea of Wind, The Shore of The Maze - Chapter 4</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Море Ветра, Берег-лабиринт. Часть 4</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Umi, Meikyuu no Kishi - Yon Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="5625" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">19</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-10-01</airdate>
<rating votes="15">9.06</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の海 迷宮の岸 五章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Sea of Wind, The Shore of The Maze - Chapter 5</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Море Ветра, Берег-лабиринт. Часть 5</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Umi, Meikyuu no Kishi - Go Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="5767" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">20</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-10-08</airdate>
<rating votes="14">9.26</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の海 迷宮の岸 終章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Sea of Wind, The Shore of The Maze - Last Chapter</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Море Ветра, Берег-лабиринт. Часть последняя</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Umi, Meikyuu no Kishi - Shuushou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="5839" recap="true" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">21</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-10-15</airdate>
<rating votes="15">6.14</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の海 迷宮の岸 転章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Sea of Wind, The Shore of The Maze - Transition Chapter</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Море Ветра, Берег-лабиринт. Интерлюдия</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Umi, Meikyuu no Kishi - Tenshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="6240" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">22</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-10-22</airdate>
<rating votes="14">8.64</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">書簡</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Letter</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Послание</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Shokan</title>
</episode>
<episode id="6241" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">23</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-10-29</airdate>
<rating votes="15">8.67</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 一章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 1</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 1</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Isshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="6250" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">24</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-11-05</airdate>
<rating votes="14">8.58</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 二章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 2</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 2</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Ni Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="6463" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">25</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-11-12</airdate>
<rating votes="15">9.31</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 三章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 3</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 3</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - San Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="6591" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">26</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-11-19</airdate>
<rating votes="14">9.49</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 四章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 4</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 4</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Yon Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="6998" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">27</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-11-26</airdate>
<rating votes="14">9.61</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 五章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 5</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 5</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Go Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="7039" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">28</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-12-03</airdate>
<rating votes="14">8.60</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 六章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 6</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 6</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Roku Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="7177" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">29</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-12-10</airdate>
<rating votes="14">9.87</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 七章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 7</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 7</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Nana Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="7458" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">30</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2002-12-17</airdate>
<rating votes="15">9.63</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 八章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 8</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 8</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Hachi Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="7595" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">31</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-01-07</airdate>
<rating votes="14">8.92</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 転章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Interlude</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Интерлюдия</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Tenshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="7747" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">32</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-01-14</airdate>
<rating votes="15">7.72</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 九章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 9</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 9</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Kyuu Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="7977" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">33</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-01-21</airdate>
<rating votes="14">9.99</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 十章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 10</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 10</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Juu Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="8227" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">34</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-01-28</airdate>
<rating votes="18">9.71</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 十一章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 11</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 11</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Juuisshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="8521" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">35</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-02-04</airdate>
<rating votes="18">10.00</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 十二章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 12</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 12</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Juuni Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="8541" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">36</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-02-18</airdate>
<rating votes="15">9.92</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 十三章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 13</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 13</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Juusan Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="8587" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">37</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-02-25</airdate>
<rating votes="18">10.00</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 十四章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 14</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 14</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Juuyon Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="8698" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">38</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-03-04</airdate>
<rating votes="23">10.00</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 十五章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Chapter 15</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть 15</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Juugo Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="8871" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">39</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-03-11</airdate>
<rating votes="56">10.00</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">風の万里 黎明の空 終章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Great Distance in The Wind, The Sky at Dawn - Last Chapter</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Путь по ветру, Небо на рассвете. Часть последняя</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaze no Banri, Reimei no Sora - Shuushou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="9392" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">40</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-07-05</airdate>
<rating votes="15">8.23</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">乗月</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Ally of the Moon</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">В лунном свете</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Jougetsu</title>
</episode>
<episode id="9531" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">41</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-07-26</airdate>
<rating votes="13">7.97</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">東の海神 西の滄海 一章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Sea God of the East, Azure Sea of the West - Chapter 1</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Бог Моря на востоке, Океан на западе. Часть 1</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Higashi no Watatsumi, Nishi no Soukai - Isshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="10570" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">42</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-08-02</airdate>
<rating votes="14">7.72</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">東の海神 西の滄海 二章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Sea God of the East, Azure Sea of the West - Chapter 2</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Бог Моря на востоке, Океан на западе. Часть 2</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Higashi no Watatsumi, Nishi no Soukai - Ni Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="13315" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">43</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-08-16</airdate>
<rating votes="14">7.72</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">東の海神 西の滄海 三章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Sea God of the East, Azure Sea of the West - Chapter 3</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Бог Моря на востоке, Океан на западе. Часть 3</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Higashi no Watatsumi, Nishi no Soukai - San Shou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="14098" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">44</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-08-23</airdate>
<rating votes="16">8.60</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">東の海神 西の滄海 終章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Sea God of the East, Azure Sea of the West - Last Chapter</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Бог Моря на востоке, Океан на западе. Часть последняя</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Higashi no Watatsumi, Nishi no Soukai - Shuushou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="14099" recap="true" update="2006-01-23">
<epno type="1">45</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2003-08-30</airdate>
<rating votes="18">3.78</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">東の海神 西の滄海 転章</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Sea God of the East, Azure Sea of the West - Transition Chapter</title>
<title xml:lang="ru">Бог Моря на востоке, Океан на западе. Интерлюдия</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Higashi no Watatsumi, Nishi no Soukai - Tenshou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="80981" update="2010-11-28">
<epno type="2">S1</epno>
<length>20</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Kobayashi Tsuneo Interview</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Du roman à l’animé</title>
</episode>
<episode id="80982" update="2010-11-28">
<epno type="3">C1</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2002-04-09</airdate>
<rating votes="2">9.64</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Opening</title>
</episode>
<episode id="80983" update="2010-11-28">
<epno type="3">C2</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2002-04-09</airdate>
<rating votes="2">7.73</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending</title>
</episode>
<episode id="120861" update="2010-08-06">
<epno type="3">C3</epno>
<length>0</length>
<rating votes="1">4.47</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 2</title>
</episode>
<episode id="168651" update="2015-05-25">
<epno type="2">S2</epno>
<length>0</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Special2</title>
</episode>
</episodes>
</anime>
