<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><anime id="9541" restricted="false">
<type>TV Series</type>
<episodecount>25</episodecount>
<startdate>2013-04-07</startdate>
<enddate>2013-09-28</enddate>
<titles>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="main">Shingeki no Kyojin</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="synonym">Advancing Giants</title>
<title xml:lang="de" type="synonym">Attack on Titan</title>
<title xml:lang="ru" type="synonym">Вторжение Гигантов</title>
<title xml:lang="el" type="synonym">Η Επίθεση των Τιτάνων</title>
<title xml:lang="he" type="synonym">מתקפת הטיטאנים</title>
<title xml:lang="ro" type="synonym">Atacul Titanilor</title>
<title xml:lang="bg" type="synonym">Поход срещу титаните</title>
<title xml:lang="bg" type="synonym">Нашествие на гиганти</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="synonym">Shingeki no Kyojin TV</title>
<title xml:lang="uk" type="synonym">На бій проти титанів</title>
<title xml:lang="uk" type="synonym">Атака Титанів</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="short">AoT</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="short">AoT TV</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">SnK</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">shingeki</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="official">進撃の巨人 attack on titan</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="official">Attack on Titan</title>
<title xml:lang="fr" type="official">L`attaque des Titans</title>
<title xml:lang="it" type="official">L`attacco dei Giganti</title>
<title xml:lang="es" type="official">Ataque a los Titanes</title>
<title xml:lang="ko" type="official">진격의 거인</title>
<title xml:lang="ar" type="official">الهجوم على العمالقة</title>
<title xml:lang="pt-BR" type="official">Ataque dos Titãs</title>
<title xml:lang="cs" type="official">Útok Titánů</title>
<title xml:lang="zh-Hant" type="official">進擊的巨人</title>
<title xml:lang="zh-Hans" type="official">进击的巨人</title>
<title xml:lang="fa" type="official">حمله به تایتان</title>
</titles>
<relatedanime>
<anime id="10944" type="Sequel">Shingeki no Kyojin Season 2</anime>
<anime id="11468" type="Alternative Setting">Shingeki! Kyojin Chuugakkou</anime>
<anime id="9826" type="Side Story">Shingeki no Kyojin OAD</anime>
<anime id="10583" type="Summary">Gekijouban Shingeki no Kyojin</anime>
</relatedanime>
<similaranime>
<anime id="4892" approval="238" total="291">Claymore</anime>
<anime id="10951" approval="87" total="105">Koutetsujou no Kabaneri</anime>
<anime id="10813" approval="19" total="35">Owari no Seraph</anime>
<anime id="10842" approval="13" total="19">God Eater</anime>
<anime id="98" approval="8" total="27">Kenpuu Denki Berserk</anime>
<anime id="10713" approval="6" total="13">Sidonia no Kishi: Daikyuu Wakusei Sen`eki</anime>
<anime id="10439" approval="6" total="12">Terra Formars</anime>
<anime id="5025" approval="4" total="18">Heroic Age</anime>
<anime id="10657" approval="3" total="13">World Trigger</anime>
<anime id="22" approval="1" total="19">Shinseiki Evangelion</anime>
<anime id="2826" approval="1" total="13">Koukyoushihen: Eureka Seven</anime>
</similaranime>
<recommendations total="82">
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="63624">Are you sick of watching moeshit ?
Then this show will be a breath of fresh air for you.
Not recommended for those that can`t stand gore.
Finally a decent adaptation of a good shounen.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="288423">Incredible anime</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="360049">awesom!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="314894">Best anime of 2013. Master piece. Don`t miss it</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="497799">Filled with non stop action and suspense. I have watched up to episode 25 and I am sure it is not finished yet. Can`t till the next episodes air.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="599448">As one of those people who watched it after the end of the season and had to endure months of hype i must say i was a little surpised. The graphic edge this was told to have seemed "weak". Disconcerting in a good way but nowhere near the hype. Nevertheless it is a must see for any anime fan.

It will glue you to your screen!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="533051">too epic...just it</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="77420">Great animation and soundtrack with an engaging storyline that keeps you hooked with the constant cliffhangers. Bad points are you sometimes feel you`re watching fillers (which I`ve found is true later on), characters pretty much don`t develop and there`s no ending as the manga is still ongoing (though it`s highly possible a sequel is going to be made).</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="632413">Really Awesome anime..

But watch out, this anime looks terrible for some people.

Don`t watch it if you afraid of bloody action</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="543137">great anime, great story love to watch it</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="572395">I must admit ... its best anime i saw in my life
amazing and fascinating work .
must see this master piece</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="83001">This series delivers intense action, but what makes it special is the courage in showing people`s ugly nature, unfairness and injustice, to the point where it`s actually asking if they are really worth saving.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="135151">Took a few eps to get into it, but enjoyed it very much. Very unique ideas. Good story/mystery.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="605483">If your looking for some action/fantasy from another made up place. This is the anime for you. Be warned there will be blood, and lot of death and gore. But other than that is a has a good solid story, a few comedy, and a ton of action.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="650045">Same premise of "kill all the _____" and protecting Humanity.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="210547">10/10 it goes in do not miss it..</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="587854">I also think its a good anime so far, BUT anyway, it has it weaknesses. The drawing quality varies sometimes. Also often fixed pictures are used and the story itself is not thaaaat innovative. Monsters killed the parents of a little child, the child wants revenge and getting a soldier. Anyway, i want to see more. :)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="465610">A nice story with interesting characters and cool animation seems promising and the manga is  epic!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="388517">really good action anime...hope there is a 2nd season coming</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="475822">The first 8 episodes or so are really great. The show moves quickly along the plot. Then it slows down almost as if they found out they were getting a second season or something. It literally takes 2 whole episodes to move from one event in the plot to the next. Reminds me of DBZ back in the day. That said it really is awesome.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="474005">this anime is off the hook. excellent design.animation and story..</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="559673">This anime is a must see and anime like these came out very rarely... if you liked claymore , berserk and 12 kingdoms there is no way , you wont like it.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="178631">Well, that was certainly something new. The main character is overly annoying but the series overall are worth watching.
Do recommend.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="302080">Absolutely breathtaking ..too bad the ending doesn`t really resolve anything. This would be an instant classic if the ending wasn`t so meh. The action is where it is at, though. Magnificent dizzying acrobatic setpieces that will have you rewinding key scenes time and again. Highly recommended.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="410851">This is absolutely A HELL Master Peice, it`s had every thing you need in anime.
In another word, you can`t miss this one, no matter what kind of anime you like.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="269108">For me it`s the best anime I`ve seen for a long time :)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="357099">Stunning animation and soundtracks, a breathtaking and well-developed plot packed with action and scenes so tense they`ll make you sit on the edge of your chair. With it`s loveable characters and realisticly detailed universe, Attack on Titan can easily be considered as one of the best anime shows of the decade.
A must watch for fans of any type of anime.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="589888">- Good storyline: Inspiring, heart-moving; blood-pumping... Its a type of anime that`ll just sucks you into it. 
- Best drawings and animations i`ve seen: Its because of the drawing that did so much efforts in expressing the utmost feelings of the characters, and maintain the actions at the top of its climax.
- Good character development: So much feels. Unbelievable depth for such an action-fantasy anime. Also, the character`s expressions are REALISTIC. It describes people`s true feeling in total despair, and the never-ending hope of humanity in that despairness.
- Extremely good music and soundtracks: What more can i say ?
- Overall, i`d like to give this a 9/10. The storyline can be really predictable sometimes, but i wouldn`t recommend you sitting there watching the anime with a speculating posture; it`s best to just sit back, relax and enjoy the anime. If you`re into fantasy, gore/thrill with a lil romance, this anime sure wont let you down</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="161106">It`s one of the more interesting show`s I`ve seen as of late. It`s fresh, I like most of the characters, the story and action is so far very intriguing. I don`t have an issue with the pacing but it`s definitely an anime that I wish would already be completed and stop at ~50 episodes. The episodes just vanish in a flash.

I wouldn`t call it a masterpiece so far, I`d give it the possibility to become one though but it all depends what direction it will take. So far it`s one of the shows I anticipate the most each week.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="239672">This series is really a suprice for me this season. It caught me right in the beginning.
The animationstyle, the story, everything. Every episode is special und the action und pressure gets up in every episode. You will always say WTF!?
This is noit a must see, its a have to see for every anime fan out there!
Highly recommend!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="273035">First anime that gived me that spark, all watched in 1 day. I rated it 10/10, it has all action, fight for those who are no longer, team fight to sacure future, survival for life, conspiracy (that plot is amazing), no mater what this is must see. Watch for you self.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="462759">this is epic!!!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="221552">Animation really good, music incredible, story interesting, voice acting topnotch.
It is a must see.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="610931">Epic!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="132520">no need to comment. just go watch it, thank me later.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="602961">Stop whatever you`re doing, inform your family/friends/colleagues that you`ll be missing for a day or two, and just watch this! And don`t forget to eat something ;-)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="456503">This is seriously by far THE BEST anime of all time. I imagine the ratings for this show on anidb will eventually surpass Code Geass. I will be shocked and appauled if they do not. I put this show on par with Game of Thrones. People die in this anime. Lots of people. People you don`t want to die. Bad s*** happens, but hey: bad s*** happens in REAL LIFE too, it`s unavoidable. This is about the human struggle and the tradegy that comes with it. Words cannot begin to describe the feels I feel when I watch this show. Dem feels bro...</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="278873">Must watch!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="631134">One of the most breathtaking and thought-provoking anime I`ve seen in a long time. No wonder it has grown such a fan-base. This will leave you hanging at the edge of your seat! After ep.7, you`re in for one hell of a ride. Must see.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="215116">Holy Hell !!!

There can`t be a better action anime than this
Must See !!!

Its an awesome setting , with great characters and character development

JUST DON`T MISS IT !!!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="307712">Inspired by Muv-Luv series (EXTRA, Unlimited, Alternative - visual novels)

Perfectly matches the manga using chronological order. First thing to understand is the characters are YOUNG and INEXPERIENCED, the manga brings fully-fledged and powerful characters in much later chapters. So complaining about inexperienced combatants is a laugh. The other point is knowing someone for few minutes, hours, or days then they die so fast. The `dying` part plays such a huge role on all minor and secondary characters. The anime ends around chapter 33 in the manga so the drama isn`t explained well like in the manga (more anime seasons will becoming). If I have to point out one thing to people, google this:

Nightcore - Reluctant Heroes

Listen to the lyrics. Very clear voice and excellent emotions invoked into the song describing the characters` inner feelings across everything when they`re on the thin thread of life and death.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="575638">awesome storyline and graphics.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="494655">If you are tired of non-sense ecchi and predictable shonens: Watch this. Definitely the best of the year. I totally recomend it.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="41593">This is indeed a must see, this anime, is a master piece so far. will get you bonded to your screen.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="461913">lots of junk out their no good story bad animation this has a good story has originality  good animation great action scenes character development is not to draw out it comes to gather nice all and i give it a 9 out of 10 defiantly a must see best stuff i have seen in awhile</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="248562">Hands down the most interesting and well-done anime I`ve ever seen! You`ll be chewing at your fingers just to see what comes next! Amazing in every aspect - animation, music, acting, story ... everything :) Epic and full of surprises! Watch it!! :)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="13780">Break Throw Achievement in this anime.
You will see Gore, Story and Passion!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="464392">Finally something that can be called a MUST SEE. There is no need for details just watch the first episode and get caught in the flow like i did!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="556870">My first ever recommendation.
I felt others have always said what was needed on other shows, so I just rate.
But this show.
While yet again others have spoken before me, saying words that I might say myself, I just need to speak out for this show.
It is far and beyond anything I expected of it, and it continues to surprise me at only 6 episodes in.
The characters, the world, the enemy, the story and potential story, nothing has grabbed me like this in a long time.
Bouncing on my seat in exciting. Jaw dropping at amazing sights and actions. Smiles all round at the carefully placed humor. Tears, tears at the tragedy of the people of this world.
A masterpiece of an anime. A masterpiece among, and comparably, to any other great stories in media.
I hope that all goes well as this continues. That they dont mess it up with some weird Dues Machina plot device.
But as for now, a MUST see.
Dare I say, perfect.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="248649">That was the best anime of this year.
Everything in this anime is at the top level.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="586352">Been a loooong time since I started watching an anime that gripped me from the very first episode. 
From that one devastating scene that changes Eren`s life, you connect with him, and you want him to kill every last Titan.
The animation and facial expressions on him, especially his eyes, make you really feel for him.
Truly gripping, and I can`t wait for the next episode.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="360204">Can`t describe this as anything other than "must see."</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="1841">Really Awesome keeps me wanting more! @@</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="621681">I am completely addicted!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="239259">i didnt enjoy watching anime since long time, specially with the latest anime mainly fan service nothing more, but this one is the best since the last 2 or 3 years as i recall, from animation to story to sound track, everything is almost excellent, must see for sure</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="307450">After episode 5 i was ``forced`` to read the manga and beleave me it goes even better :)
An absolute master piece.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="177141">Yeah, if you`re a seinen fan, yeah, 
it really is that good.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="301941">Watch it. This is simply awesome. People dying, twisted story and more :P</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="161249">Great story with superb art!  I loved it from start to finish!  The only downside will be the long wait for the second season to come out.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="38231">The story is so unforgiving. It`s heartbreaking and fearsome how much this gets under your skin. I`ve waited ages to get something like this just sucks you in! Don`t make the error and miss on this one!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="403846">No doubt the best anime of 2013 so far. And it keeps getting better and better.

The cover on anidb is lame tho.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="246107">If you like Gundam UC, Berserk, and Fist of North star , you should watch this anime. I guarantee 100% you will like it.
If you like lame shoujou, gymnastic , loli, boring long-winded conversation kind of anime, then this anime is not for you. It is as simple as that. 
Different anime appeals to different type of otaku.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="229307">One of the best anime so far .
you have to see it to understand what i mean 
this anime well catch your mind and ur heart .

my rating is &amp;gt; 10\10  Without questions
if its up to me I give him ten of awards.

You can`t miss awesome anime like this 
YOU MUST SEE IT FOR SURE</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="146333">pure epicness !! a must see anime</recommendation>
</recommendations>
<url>http://shingeki.tv/</url>
<creators>
<name id="3203" type="Chief Animation Direction">Chiba Takaaki</name>
<name id="6331" type="Chief Animation Direction">Asano Kyouji</name>
<name id="34645" type="Animation Work">Wit Studio</name>
<name id="6331" type="Character Design">Asano Kyouji</name>
<name id="2702" type="Series Composition">Kobayashi Yasuko</name>
<name id="1523" type="Direction">Araki Tetsurou</name>
<name id="6722" type="Music">Sawano Hiroyuki</name>
<name id="34803" type="Original Work">Isayama Hajime</name>
<name id="522" type="Chief Animation Direction">Kadowaki Satoshi</name>
</creators>
<description>Several hundred years ago, humans were nearly exterminated by titans. Titans are typically several stories tall, seem to have no intelligence, devour human beings and, worst of all, seem to do it for the pleasure rather than as a food source. A small percentage of humanity survived by walling themselves in a city protected by extremely high walls, even taller than the biggest of titans.
Flash forward to the present and the city has not seen a titan in over 100 years. Teenage boy http://anidb.net/ch51115 [Eren] and his foster sister http://anidb.net/ch51116 [Mikasa] witness something horrific as the city walls are destroyed by a super titan that appears out of thin air. As the smaller titans flood the city, the two kids watch in horror as their mother is eaten alive. Eren vows that he will murder every single titan and take revenge for all of mankind.
Source: MangaHelpers
Note: The last episode received a pre-airing in Tokyo, Marunouchi Piccadilly 1 theater. TV broadcast took place after midnight, a few hours later.</description>
<ratings>
<permanent count="6241">8.24</permanent>
<temporary count="6356">8.26</temporary>
<review count="8">7.08</review>
</ratings>
<picture>133345.jpg</picture>
<resources>
<resource type="1">
<externalentity>
<identifier>14950</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="2">
<externalentity>
<identifier>19391</identifier>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<identifier>19285</identifier>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<identifier>16498</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="3">
<externalentity>
<identifier>5300</identifier>
<identifier>ymloqc</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="4">
<externalentity>
<url>http://www.production-ig.co.jp/works/shingeki-no-kyojin</url>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<url>http://shingeki.tv/</url>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="5">
<externalentity>
<url>http://www.funimation.com/shows/attack-on-titan</url>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="6">
<externalentity>
<identifier>Attack_on_Titan</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="7">
<externalentity>
<identifier>進撃の巨人</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="8">
<externalentity>
<identifier>2935</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="9">
<externalentity>
<identifier>344548</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="10">
<externalentity>
<identifier>15934</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="11">
<externalentity>
<identifier>mediadb/media/3968</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>attack-on-titan</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
<tags>
<tag id="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>meta tags</name>
<description>These tags are used for maintenance.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="36" parentid="2607" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-04-17">
<name>military</name>
<description>The military, also known as the armed forces, are forces authorized and legally entitled to use deadly force so as to support the interests of the state and its citizens. The task of the military is usually defined as defence of the state and its citizens and the prosecution of war against foreign powers. The military may also have additional functions within a society, including construction, emergency services, social ceremonies, and guarding critical areas.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="505" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-02-08">
<name>giant</name>
</tag>
<tag id="922" parentid="2606" infobox="true" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-04">
<name>shounen</name>
<description>In the context of manga and associated media, shounen, literally meaning "youth" and often also specifically "boy", refers to a male audience roughly between the ages of 10 and 18.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1955" parentid="2925" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-05-18">
<name>child soldier</name>
<description>Untrained and as yet immature, children are expediently thrust into the role of warriors to protect god, king, and country. Not having even finished school, they are inexplicably designated to elite status or roles, typically requiring months of training and years of experience. All the more so with "experimental" equipment or weapons of mass destruction.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2604" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-04-02">
<name>content indicators</name>
<description>The content indicators branch is intended to be a less geographically specific tool than the `age rating` used by convention, for warning about things that might cause offence. Obviously there is still a degree of subjectivity involved, but hopefully it will prove useful for parents with delicate children, or children with delicate parents.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-28">
<name>dynamic</name>
<description>Some of the central structural elements in anime are: 
Plot Continuity 
How does the plot or several plots unfold. Are they a strictly linear retelling of one big continuing story, a serial, possibly with several side stories, or is the content chopped into a set of unconnected episodes, only sharing the same setting and characters?
Stereotype Characters
Then there is the question of the character set presentation. Is it completely original, or is it your usual stereotypical character cast. Both choices have their merit, for example it would not really make much sense to reinvent the wheel for a harem anime. Fans of that genre come to expect their favourite stereotype protagonists.
Plot Twists
Finally there is the question of how complex the plot / the story unfolds. Are there side-plots that merge into the main plot leading to unexpected plot twists, or is the anime quite predictable? The latter would not be appropriate for detective stories. In harem anime on the other hand a foreseeable outcome is actually something the fans will come to expect.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2606" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-18">
<name>target audience</name>
<description>Anime, like everything else in the modern world, is targeted towards specific audiences, both implicitly by the creators and overtly by the marketing. While categories are associated with specific sex and age groups, this is not a bar on the anime being enjoyed by people who don`t fit into that band; not only do crossover titles exist, but the categories also have a considerable following outside their main demographic, and a person might as well enjoy anime from all categories. Still, does not invalidate the usefulness of marking a title as one of the categories; the same themes will likely be treated differently in anime geared for different audiences. Only one should not jump the gun and assume that a title will be more or less serious or present content in this or that way due to its target audience, or conversely assume the target audience on the content and its presentation alone. As such, the audience categories help form a broad impression of how a title might work with the announced themes, but offer little to no in-depth information about specific content or its treatment.
The audience categories originate from manga magazines, which group titles of a same intended audience into a magazine that is advertised as belonging to that category, and so manga-based anime will have the category from their parent work. As for anime based on other works, the audience is often debatable, but comparing information such as time slot to the manga-based anime generally helps figure out the most likely possibility.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-29">
<name>themes</name>
<description>Themes describe the very central elements important to the anime stories. They set the backdrop against which the protagonists must face their challenges. Be it School Life, present Daily Life, Military action, Cyberpunk, Law and Order detective work, Sports, or the Underworld. These are only but a few of the more typical backgrounds for anime plots. Add to that a Conspiracy setting with a possible tragic outcome, the Themes span most of the imaginable subject matter relevant to anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2609" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-22">
<name>original work</name>
<description>What the anime is based on! Mostly of academic interest, but a useful bit of info, hinting at the possible depth of story.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-08">
<name>elements</name>
<description>Next to Themes setting the backdrop for the protagonists in anime, there are the more detailed plot Elements that centre on character interactions: "What do characters do to each other or what is done to them?". Is it violent Action, an awe-inspiring Adventure in a foreign place, the gripping life of a Detective, a slapstick Comedy, an Ecchi Harem anime, a SciFi epic, or some Fantasy travelling adventure?</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2618" parentid="2841" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-07">
<name>collateral damage</name>
<description>The usually action orientated anime does not only show large amounts of combat and weapon use, but also the incidental massive destruction of property, often due to the inability of the protagonists to aim properly.
Example: Mecha duking it out in a densely populated urban area.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2636" parentid="2846" weight="200" localspoiler="true" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-10-06">
<name>human enhancement</name>
<description>The enhancement of humans can take various forms: It can be something comparatively non-intrusive as a power-up drug, a form of machine implantation or cyberization ("SAC Solid State Society"), or outright - possibly atrocious - genetic manipulation ("Ao no 6-gou"). Plot-wise enhanced protagonists in anime usually have to pay a price for their enhancements, be it physical or mental.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2750" parentid="2604" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-07-28">
<name>violence</name>
<description>Physical force against self or other, compelling action against one`s will on pain of being hurt.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2798" parentid="2609" infobox="true" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-07">
<name>manga</name>
<description>Manga is the lifeblood that drives the anime industry. Everything and its mother is based on manga. However! There are exceptions where the manga was not the basis for the anime.
It`s common practice to make manga adaptations of many popular anime, there`s a manga based on Evangelion, and two (one shounen and one shoujo) based on each of Escaflowne and Mahou Tsukai Tai. Also it`s quite common to release manga and anime versions of a story in parallel, for instance Nadesico and Shoujo Kakumei Utena. There are also cases where an anime continues in a manga, as in the case of Angel Beats! and Angel Beats: Heaven`s Door, or reverse.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2841" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="500" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-09-08">
<name>action</name>
<description>Action anime usually involve a fairly straightforward story of good guys versus bad guys, where most disputes are resolved by using physical force. It often contains a lot of shooting, explosions and fighting.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2844" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-05-07">
<name>angst</name>
<description>A feeling of general discomfort and uneasiness is present due to either trivial or more serious reasons, often accompanied by depression.
Warning: may contain copious amounts of brooding and sighing.
Etymology: "Angst" is a German word meaning fear or anxiety.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2846" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>science fiction</name>
<description>Science fiction stories usually focus on how situations could be different in the future when we are more technologically advanced; due to either our own achievements or having met with other civilizations whom we have learned from.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2849" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2005-05-07">
<name>fantasy</name>
<description>Fantasy is a genre of fiction that uses magic and other supernatural phenomena as a primary element of plot, theme, or setting. Many works within the genre take place in fictional worlds where magic is common. Fantasy is generally distinguished from science fiction and horror by the expectation that it steers clear of (pseudo-)scientific and macabre themes, respectively, though there is a great deal of overlap between the three (which are subgenres of speculative fiction).
In popular culture, the genre of fantasy is dominated by its medievalist form, especially since the worldwide success of The Lord of the Rings books by J. R. R. Tolkien. In its broadest sense however, fantasy comprises works by many writers, artists, filmmakers, and musicians, from ancient myths and legends to many recent works embraced by a wide audience today.
Fantasy is a vibrant area of academic study in a number of disciplines (English, cultural studies, comparative literature, history, medieval studies). Work in this area ranges widely, from the structuralist theory of Tzvetan Todorov, which emphasizes the fantastic as a liminal space, to work on the connections (political, historical, literary) between medievalism and popular culture
Source: Wiki</description>
<picurl>68768.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2850" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-10-25">
<name>adventure</name>
<description>Adventures are exciting stories, with new experiences or exotic locales. Adventures are designed to provide an action-filled, energetic experience for the viewer. Rather than the predominant emphasis on violence and fighting that is found in pure action anime, however, the viewer of adventures can live vicariously through the travels, conquests, explorations, creation of empires, struggles and situations that confront the main characters, actual historical figures or protagonists. Under the category of adventures, we can include traditional swashbucklers, serialized films, and historical spectacles, searches or expeditions for lost continents, "jungle" and "desert" epics, treasure hunts and quests, disaster films, and heroic journeys or searches for the unknown. Adventure films are often, but not always, set in an historical period, and may include adapted stories of historical or literary adventure heroes, kings, battles, rebellion, or piracy.</description>
<picurl>178879.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2851" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-15">
<name>horror</name>
<description>The horror cinematic genre is characterized by the attempt to make the viewer experience dread, fear, terror, or horror. Often their plots involve the intrusion of an evil force, event or personage, sometimes of supernatural origin, on the mundane world and the consequences thereof.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2870" parentid="2846" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-17">
<name>steampunk</name>
<description>Steampunk is a sub-genre of science fiction that typically features steam-powered machinery, especially in a setting inspired by industrialized Western civilization during the 19th century. Steampunk works are often set in an alternative history of the 19th century`s British Victorian era or American "Wild West", in a post-apocalyptic future during which steam power has regained mainstream use, or in a fantasy world that similarly employs steam power.
Noteworthy attributes of the theme include large amounts smoke pollution from wood or coal burning, the affinity to metal constructs like cogs and metal tubing, and the mechanization of everyday objects.
Steampunk perhaps most recognisably features anachronistic technologies or retro-futuristic inventions as people in the 19th century might have envisioned them, and is likewise rooted in the era`s perspective on fashion, culture, architectural style, and art.
Such technology may include fictional machines like those found in the works of H. G. Wells and Jules Verne, or the modern authors Philip Pullman, Scott Westerfeld, Stephen Hunt and China Miéville. Other examples of steampunk contain alternative history-style presentations of such technology as lighter-than-air airships, analog computers, or such digital mechanical computers as Charles Babbage`s Analytical Engine.
Steampunk can also exemplify everything that is bad about unrestrained technological progress (dead matter), when compared to life and nature. The anime usually makes a point to propound the latter.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
<picurl>162830.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2874" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-16">
<name>disaster</name>
<description>A disaster is a large-scale natural or human-made situation that causes great loss of or threat to life, health, property, or environment in such a way that society or environment are affected substantially.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2877" parentid="2607" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-02-27">
<name>revenge</name>
<description>A primary factor that drives the plot forward, is the almost obsessive desire of one of the characters to get back at someone else.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2887" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-16">
<name>tragedy</name>
<description>Tragedy is a form of drama characterized by seriousness and dignity, usually involving a conflict between a character and some higher power, such as the law, the gods, fate, or society.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2923" parentid="2874" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-06-25">
<name>post-apocalypse</name>
<description>An anime that takes place on future Earth (or it could be an alternative universe) after a major cataclysm has occurred. World War III, an alien invasion, plague, global warming or some other general disaster are common themes to build a post-apocalyptic world upon, where the effects were severe enough that mankind barely survived.
The time frame may be immediately after the catastrophe, focusing on the travails or psychology of survivors, or considerably later, often including the theme that the existence of pre-catastrophe civilization has been forgotten (or mythologised). Post-apocalyptic stories often take place in an agrarian, non-technological future world, or a world where only scattered elements of technology remain. There is a considerable degree of blurring between post-apocalyptic fiction and that which deals with false utopias or dystopian societies.</description>
<picurl>42081.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2925" parentid="2874" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-07">
<name>war</name>
<description>War is a phenomenon of organized violent conflict, typified by extreme aggression, societal disruption and adaptation, and high mortality. The objective of warfare differs in accord with a group`s role in a conflict: The goals of offensive warfare are typically the submission, assimilation or destruction of another group, while the goals of defensive warfare are simply the repulsion of the offensive force and, often, survival itself. Relative to each other, combatants in warfare are called enemies. The terms military, militant, and militarism each refer to fundamental aspects of war, i.e. the organized group, the combative individual, and the supportive ethos (respectively).
Source: wiki</description>
<picurl>56441.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-12-04">
<name>unsorted</name>
<description>a bunch of tags that still need to be either deleted or moved into proper places.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3316" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-08-10">
<name>despair</name>
<description>Involves characters that may be lost in negatively emotional atmospheres created through feelings of hopelessness and suffering.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3411" parentid="2841" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-24">
<name>fighting</name>
<description>For some reason or other one faction has to take it out on some opponent via fight or battle. Typical examples of this are all the anime with "endless pointless fighting" tag.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3750" parentid="6151" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-09-08">
<name>thick line animation</name>
<description>The characters are drawn with a thicker outline than is usually seen in anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3805" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2013-11-30">
<name>European stylised</name>
<description>The anime is set in a fictional Europe. Imagine an architectural and cultural mix of London, Paris, Rome, Berlin, Prague, and other cities in the 19th century.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3809" parentid="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-05-24">
<name>character driven</name>
<description>The main appeal of the show is the way the characters are portrayed and interact, focusing on dialogue, spending time together or getting to know each other. These anime are not "story-less" but story is secondary to character development and the characters themselves and what they experience.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3822" parentid="6230" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-03-15">
<name>strong male lead</name>
<description>The lead male protagonist in this anime shows backbone, is competent, and does not shy away from seemingly insurmountable objectives.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4022" parentid="6230" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-11-29">
<name>strong female lead</name>
<description>The lead female character has a strong personality and plays a part that is not the typical damsel-in-distress role. 
This is the exact opposite of the “damsel in distress” tag.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4083" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-11-04">
<name>drastic change of life</name>
<description>One or more characters in this series go through an event that makes them change their way of life drastically and permanently. This change might be voluntary, or against the character`s will.
Some examples might be an accident, the gaining of superpowers, or simply graduating.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4096" parentid="2750" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-03-23">
<name>gore</name>
<description>A Splatter film or Gore film is a sub-genre of horror film that deliberately focuses on graphic portrayals of gore and graphic violence. These films, through the use of special effects and excessive blood and guts, tend to display an overt interest in the vulnerability of the human body and the theatricality of its mutilation. Due to their willingness to portray images society might consider shocking, splatter films share some ideological grounds with the transgressive art movement. The term "splatter cinema" was coined by George A. Romero to describe his film Dawn of the Dead, though Dawn of the Dead is generally considered by critics to have higher aspirations, such as social commentary, than to be simply exploitative for its own sake.
[Source: wiki]</description>
<picurl>32491.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="4149" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-05-22">
<name>non-blood-related siblings</name>
<description>The siblings, usually living under the same roof, are not blood related.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4182" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="true" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-01-22">
<name>hidden power</name>
<description>For some reason or another a character has powers (or potential) he or she can`t access and may not even know about. 
In some anime these hidden powers are used quite frequently to overcome an enemy or threat (e.g. Naruto, Bleach).</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4215" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2013-03-30">
<name>daikaijuu</name>
<description>Literally translating to giant monster, daikaiju is an element found often in Japanese entertainment. Although usually for the science fiction genre it is also often used in horror, fantasy, mecha, and to a lesser extent comedy. Any monster that towers over a house technically qualifies as a daikaiju. Some anime, usually mecha, will go as far as calling their daikaiju with a specific title.</description>
<picurl>60039.png</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="4226" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-21">
<name>paradise lost</name>
<description>Derived from the Biblical story of the Fall of Man: the temptation of Adam and Eve by the fallen angel Satan and their expulsion from the Garden of Eden.
This tag is used to demonstrate the unbearable loss, the feeling of losing everything along with every single bit of happiness. It prerequisites a small peaceful period of happiness. The main reason for losing "his/her paradise" can either be the death/sacrifice of an important character or even a betrayal. Usually the anime loses a lot of its former glory afterwards.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4251" parentid="6230" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-11-16">
<name>ensemble cast</name>
<description>A show with an ensemble cast focuses on a larger group of characters rather than on a smaller number of them. As such, it doesn`t really have a "main" or "lead" character; instead, such a show has a group of central characters, all of whom play an important part in the show`s grander scheme.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4257" parentid="2607" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-08-07">
<name>survival</name>
<description>The theme/genre of survival typically depicts the act or process of continuing to live, generally in a hostile, possibly post-apocalyptic environment. Survival-centered media tends to be dark, set most commonly in a contemporary context, and generally leads either to small groups of people forming closely knit and functional units or to individuals turning against their fellows in a return to the survival of the fittest.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4299" parentid="6148" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2015-04-29">
<name>flashback</name>
<description>A flashback is a moment in which someone remembers events from their past. In fiction, flashbacks are used primarily to give insight into a character`s mind or to reveal information which had been previously kept from the audience. They normally consist essentially of new content; in some cases, they may also consist of short snippets of already displayed content, as in http://anidb.net/ch23266 [Okabe Rintarou]`s flashbacks in http://anidb.net/a7729 [Steins;Gate], but even in these cases the flashbacks are used to look into what the character is thinking. As such, they are different from and should not be confused with recaps, which are old content being shown again for no particular purpose other than padding or reminding the audience of the events up to that point. As a rule of thumb, to qualify as a flashback, the scene must advance the show`s content in some way or form; anything else is just a recap.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4316" parentid="6242" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-11-20">
<name>murder</name>
<description>To bring about someone else`s death, by a voluntary act. Whether it comes from the killer`s own hand or by exposing the victim to life-threatening circumstances, the result is foreseeable and sought by the perpetrator.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4340" parentid="6242" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-09-26">
<name>suicide</name>
<description>One or several characters in this anime commit suicide.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4537" parentid="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-02-15">
<name>time skip</name>
<description>The plot features at least one skip or jump in time.
Example: A skip from the present into the past, or time skips in increments, e.g. every hour there is a time skip by a day.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4565" parentid="2925" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-08-17">
<name>war-zone realities</name>
<description>War is hell. This tag is for when characters experience the hell of war... not just the exciting stuff blowing up part.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4611" parentid="6230" weight="0" localspoiler="true" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-22">
<name>nearly almighty protagonist</name>
<description>Man 1: "Hey man, did you see me take down that guy over there, there`s no way he could have survived that!"
Man 2: "Yeah I know what you mean, it would take the strength of 1 million men to be able to ..... HE`S GETTING BACK UP!!?!?"
*synonymous jaws dropping*
This anime`s main character is comparable to the gods themselves in terms of resistibility, strength and/or downright bad-assery. Whenever they seem as if the fire inside has burnt out, they rise from the ashes with enough tenacity and ferocity to vanquish any foe that dare stand against them.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4753" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2010-03-15">
<name>disturbing</name>
<description>Watching the show may cause the viewer to have unpleasant feelings.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5816" parentid="4316" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-10-03">
<name>massacre</name>
<description>Mass murder.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5890" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2011-04-10">
<name>medieval</name>
<description>Setting is placed in the so called "dark ages". It can be either European style, oriental style or Chinese/Japanese style of castles, armour, ways of fighting etc.. 
Also the average education is weak, superstition is high and fights are settled on foot or horseback. Furthermore the level to technology is rather low.
Note: The perceived low level of cultural and technological evolution may be offset by an influx of magic (fantasy stories) or very sophisticated technology that the inhabitants choose to make less obvious to the viewer.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5918" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2011-07-09">
<name>tragic beginning</name>
<description>Either the first episode of the anime depicts a tragedy of cataclysmic proportions for the protagonist, or the whole story has its roots in some ill-fated, dreadful event in the protagonist`s past, and we learn of it later in the anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5965" parentid="6247" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="true" verified="false" update="2015-02-10">
<name>incomplete story</name>
<description>The show does not cover all of the original work (if present) or was cancelled prematurely, leaving plot lines unresolved or aborting character development. Sometimes the show runs through all its initially slotted episodes and adapts all of the original work (if applicable) but fails to present a proper ending, leaving viewers wondering whether they`re missing the final episodes.
In some cases, this may overlap with the studio forging an anime-original ending. Such an ending normally manages to allow the show to "finish", but may still suffer from incomplete story issues.
An incomplete storyline is not to be confused with the sequel bait, which is when the story presented by the show is finished but leaves enough room for a sequel to be produced. Sometimes this goes as far as to present a new potential problem in the last few minutes; that is usual for after-credits footage in movies.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6062" parentid="6233" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-04-05">
<name>heroic sacrifice</name>
<description>"In order to save the many, the few will need to sacrifice their lives..." or so this character may think. 
In a seemingly hopeless situation, against impossible odds, the character does not choose the path of the coward and run, he or she chooses to bravely face the enemy, fully aware that this will mean death.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6148" parentid="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>TO BE MOVED TO EPISODE</name>
<description>Tags under this parent tag are going to be moved to episode tags and removed from the anime they`re currently assigned to. They will be blocked from the anime system once that move is complete. Please help with that job if you know what episodes they should be assigned to.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6149" parentid="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>TO BE MOVED TO CHARACTER</name>
<description>Tags under this parent tag are going to be moved to character tags and removed from the anime they`re currently assigned to. They will be blocked from the anime system once that move is complete. Please help with that job if you know what characters they should be assigned to.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6151" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>technical aspects</name>
<description>It may sometimes be useful to know about technical aspects of a show, such as information about its broadcasting or censorship. Such information can be found here.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6230" parentid="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-20">
<name>cast</name>
</tag>
<tag id="6233" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-08-11">
<name>tropes</name>
<description>A trope is a commonly recurring literary and rhetorical devices, motifs or clichés in creative works. This use is a broader redefining of a literary trope, the use of figurative language, via word, phrase, or even an image, for artistic effect, such as using a figure of speech.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6242" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-29">
<name>death</name>
</tag>
<tag id="6247" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-10-31">
<name>ending tags that need merging</name>
</tag>
</tags>
<characters>
<character id="51114" type="main character in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="115">3.58</rating>
<name>Armin Arlert</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Eren`s best friend, he is physically and emotionally weak. His strategic abilities have saved Eren and Mikasa several times. He himself does not notice the things he does for Eren and Mikasa, and believes himself to be completely incompetent and hates himself for having to rely of Eren and Mikasa.</description>
<picture>134316.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="11" picture="32253.jpg">Inoue Marina</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51115" type="main character in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="161">3.89</rating>
<name>Eren Yeager</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Eren Yeager is Shingeki`s protagonist. His adoptive sister, Mikasa, notes on numerous occasions that he acts on impulse without thinking things through, and she often pulls/carries/throws him when he starts fighting with others to protect him from himself. Along with Mikasa, he tends to spend his free time with their mutual friend, Armin.
When Eren was a child, he saved Mikasa from being killed when visiting her home with his father. Three men - killers of her parents - were in her house, and he killed two of them--one by slitting his throat and the other by charging at with a quickly assembled spear. Mikasa herself killed the third man when he attempted to strangle Eren. After this, he gave Mikasa his scarf and took her into his family.
Later, when the giants invaded his home, he could only watch on as his mother - trapped under the rubble of their house - was eaten by a giant. This event made him swear that he`d kill every giant and not live a life cowering in fear.
Sometime after this - before the timeskip that jumped a few years ahead, to when he became a soldier - his father injected him with something. It`s unknown what at this time but it turns out, because of the injection, Eren can regenerate lost limbs and transform into a somewhat out of control giant.</description>
<picture>134314.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1678" picture="68277.jpg">Kaji Yuuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51116" type="main character in" update="2014-02-03">
<rating votes="284">7.51</rating>
<name>Mikasa Ackerman</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Mikasa Ackerman is the adoptive sister of Eren and mutual childhood friend of Armin, Mikasa hides her emotions but cares deeply for Eren--never hesitating to cry with tears of joy or despair depending on what happens to him. She shares an unbreakable bond with Eren following events in their past, and his mother requesting that she protect him made her even more overly protective of him than she was beforehand.
Subtle (and not-so-subtle) hints throughout the manga suggest she loves Eren as a man, rather than as a brother. However, in the first four volumes he hasn`t shown any such feelings in return; while he does show hints indicating he cares for her, it is still not known if it is as his sister or as a woman.
When Mikasa`s parents were murdered, and she was tied-up on the floor, Eren saved her life - when visiting by chance with his father - by killing two of the three men who killed her parents, in spite of him only being a child at the time. And then, when the third man was strangling a helpless Eren after catching him off-guard, she picked up a knife off the floor and stabbed the man in the back; killing him.
Afterward, Eren gave Mikasa his scarf - which, even many years later, she still wears - and made sure she understood that he, and his parents, were now her family. Because of his heroics and this gesture, she feels her life is Eren`s now, because - in her mind - she already died once.</description>
<picture>134315.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="443" picture="145927.jpg">Ishikawa Yui</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51167" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="64">5.74</rating>
<name>Jean Kirstein</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Ranked 6th of the trainee class. Extremely pessimistic about the War with the Titans. He ends up leading the people on the supply mission for gas. From the Trost District. He is highly competent at the three dimensional maneuver and highly skilled at efficiently using it. Good at asserting his situation at any given time, but is far too quick to unsheathe his sword. He is also prone to sparking conflict.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>134317.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="181" picture="171560.jpg">Taniyama Kishou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51168" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="94">6.40</rating>
<name>Annie Leonhart</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Ranked 4th of the trainee class. A stoic girl whose father trained her in hand to hand combat. She strikes with a perfect penetration angle. She is a solitary type, and solidarity does not come to her easily.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>134318.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3198" picture="160468.jpg">Shimamura Yuu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51169" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="103">7.14</rating>
<name>Sasha Blouse</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Ranked 9th of the trainee class. A thief from the mountain Daupa District, she joined in order to find tasty things to eat. Lightning fast, with an uncanny intuition, but her eccentricity makes her unfit for group operations.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>134321.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="79" picture="34814.jpg">Kobayashi Yuu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51170" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="69">6.22</rating>
<name>Krista Lenz</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Ranked 10th in the trainee class (due to Ymir holding back during the assessment) and later was put into the 41st squad during the invasion of Trost in the year 850. A kind and beautiful girl who is able to show great care for others, she has been described as a "goddess". However, she later develops a fear of facing the Titans and spends much of her time around Ymir.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>134323.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4007" picture="25937.jpg">Mikami Shiori</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51171" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="37">2.77</rating>
<name>Connie Springer</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Ranked 8th of the trainee class, an upbeat and naive personality. Aims to apply to the scouting legion because he was motivated by Eren. From Ragako District. Good balance especially good at making tight turns but he is slow to the uptake, and his grasp of strategy is often less than perfect.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>134324.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="175" picture="167565.jpg">Shimono Hiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51172" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="20">2.80</rating>
<name>Marco Bott</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Ranked 7th of the trainee class. Joined to be part of the Police force because he wants to work for the King. From Jinae District.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>134325.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="29979" picture="79261.jpg">Oosaka Ryouta</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="53532" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="34">5.90</rating>
<name>Reiner Braun</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Ranked 2nd of the trainee class, is considered strong-willed with a solid constitution and most adept at gaining the trust of his comrades.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>134326.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3709" picture="84359.jpg">Hosoya Yoshimasa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="53533" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="22">3.09</rating>
<name>Bertolt Hoover</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Ranked 3rd of the trainee class. Highly proficient in various hand to hand combat styles. He seems to have great potential but lacks in self-confidence and has a tendency to leave it to others whenever it comes to showing assertiveness.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>134327.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="5039" picture="33316.jpg">Hashizume Tomohisa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="53534" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="17">2.96</rating>
<name>Hannes</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>139129.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="168" picture="80607.jpg">Fujiwara Keiji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="53535" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="33">3.65</rating>
<name>Ymir</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>134328.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1673" picture="41835.jpg">Fujita Saki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54440" type="secondary cast in" update="2014-05-26">
<rating votes="217">8.61</rating>
<name>Levi Ackerman</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Known as humanity`s most powerful soldier. He is a clean-freak. While it is said that he is blunt and unapproachable, it is noted that he has a strong respect for structure and discipline. The rumors are that he was originally part of underground crime before he became a soldier.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>140561.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="224" picture="79056.jpg">Kamiya Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54441" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="94">8.04</rating>
<name>Erwin Smith</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140563.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="250" picture="157976.jpg">Ono Daisuke</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54442" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-11-17">
<rating votes="109">7.42</rating>
<name>Hanji Zoe</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A scientist studying the Titans, showing no real fear in them and intense interest in Eren`s new physiology as a Titan. Considered weird by the rest of her comrades, only a few tolerate her obsession with Titans. In the past, she used to have a strong hatred against Titans until the death of her comrade Ilse convinced her to see the Titans in a different light. Hanji is not only responsible for the research the Survey Corps have on the Titans but also the special weapons they use, such as a barrel that fires multiple grappling hooks to capture Titans alive.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>140562.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="566" picture="25408.jpg">Paku Romi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54899" type="appears in" update="2013-04-10">
<rating votes="7">5.05</rating>
<name>Karla Yeager</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135053.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3890" picture="186170.jpg">Takamori Yoshino</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54900" type="appears in" update="2013-04-10">
<rating votes="2">4.41</rating>
<name>Nick Shisai</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135054.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3064" picture="24692.jpg">Asou Tomohisa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54901" type="appears in" update="2013-04-10">
<rating votes="5">3.30</rating>
<name>Grisha Yeager</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135052.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2585" picture="22579.jpg">Tsuchida Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54902" type="appears in" update="2013-04-17">
<rating votes="10">7.40</rating>
<name>Keith Shardis</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135336.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4039" picture="91415.jpg">Mogami Tsuguo</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54903" type="appears in" update="2014-02-15">
<rating votes="2">4.41</rating>
<name>Hugo</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>150274.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="399" picture="17244.jpg">Suyama Akio</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54904" type="appears in" update="2014-02-15">
<rating votes="2">4.41</rating>
<name>Moses</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>150277.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="33595" picture="188727.jpg">Masumoto Takuya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54905" type="appears in" update="2013-04-10">
<rating votes="2">4.41</rating>
<name>Moses no Haha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135071.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="6871" picture="51988.jpg">Terase Kyouko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54906" type="appears in" update="2013-04-10">
<rating votes="3">3.67</rating>
<name>Kodomo</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135069.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="31646" picture="85192.jpg">Satou Megumi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54907" type="appears in" update="2013-04-10">
<rating votes="2">4.41</rating>
<name>Haha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135070.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="32916" picture="89530.jpg">Kawasaki Meiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54908" type="appears in" update="2013-04-10">
<rating votes="4">2.96</rating>
<name>Sakanaya</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135072.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="24404" picture="68958.jpg">Murakami Yuuya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="54912" type="appears in" update="2013-05-03">
<rating votes="3">3.92</rating>
<name>Dai 104-ki Kunren Heidan</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="3">Organization</charactertype>
<picture>136164.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="54913" type="appears in" update="2013-05-02">
<rating votes="11">8.99</rating>
<name>Chousa Heidan</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="3">Organization</charactertype>
<picture>136163.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="54914" type="appears in" update="2014-02-15">
<rating votes="3">8.81</rating>
<name>Chousa Heidan Tokubetsu Sakusen Han</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="3">Organization</charactertype>
<picture>150272.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="54915" type="appears in" update="2013-05-02">
<rating votes="4">3.68</rating>
<name>Chuuton Heidan</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="3">Organization</charactertype>
<picture>136162.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="55024" type="appears in" update="2013-04-17">
<rating votes="5">3.24</rating>
<name>Armin no Sofu</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135335.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2279" picture="23207.jpg">Satou Masaharu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55211" type="appears in" update="2013-05-04">
<rating votes="3">3.92</rating>
<name>Samuel</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136188.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="169" picture="16976.jpg">Takahashi Kenji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55212" type="appears in" update="2013-06-16">
<rating votes="5">3.84</rating>
<name>Daz</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>138605.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="20532" picture="188517.jpg">Takubo Shuuhei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55213" type="appears in" update="2013-04-21">
<rating votes="5">4.25</rating>
<name>Thomas Wagner</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135617.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="33630" picture="92065.jpg">Susaki Shigeyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55214" type="appears in" update="2013-05-04">
<rating votes="3">3.29</rating>
<name>Hanna</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136189.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="31646" picture="85192.jpg">Satou Megumi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55215" type="appears in" update="2013-05-04">
<rating votes="3">4.45</rating>
<name>Franz</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136190.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="36642" picture="188475.jpg">Ookuma Kenta</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55216" type="appears in" update="2013-04-21">
<rating votes="5">3.95</rating>
<name>Mina Carolina</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135621.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="10759" picture="38748.jpg">Anzai Chika</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55247" type="appears in" update="2013-04-21">
<rating votes="3">3.69</rating>
<name>Megane no Kyoukan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>135643.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="24404" picture="68958.jpg">Murakami Yuuya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55560" type="appears in" update="2013-05-02">
<rating votes="5">2.67</rating>
<name>Kyoukan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136159.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="24404" picture="68958.jpg">Murakami Yuuya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55561" type="appears in" update="2013-05-03">
<rating votes="10">1.80</rating>
<name>Kenpei Dan</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="3">Organization</charactertype>
<picture>136165.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="55580" type="appears in" update="2013-05-05">
<rating votes="6">3.87</rating>
<name>Anka Rheinberger</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136258.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="9124" picture="186845.jpg">Hayama Ikumi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55581" type="appears in" update="2013-06-08">
<rating votes="6">4.65</rating>
<name>Ian Dietrich</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>138079.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="24404" picture="68958.jpg">Murakami Yuuya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55582" type="appears in" update="2013-05-19">
<rating votes="6">2.54</rating>
<name>Kitts Verman</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136782.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="78" picture="16686.jpg">Shimura Tomoyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55583" type="appears in" update="2013-05-05">
<rating votes="3">3.92</rating>
<name>Gustav</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136257.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2004" picture="67664.jpg">Shinomiya Gou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55584" type="appears in" update="2013-05-05">
<rating votes="15">9.12</rating>
<name>Dott Pixis</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136256.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="284" picture="43153.jpg">Tanaka Masahiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55585" type="appears in" update="2014-02-15">
<rating votes="2">6.41</rating>
<name>Nack Tierce</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>150276.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="10190" picture="48563.jpg">Higuchi Tomoyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55586" type="appears in" update="2013-05-05">
<rating votes="9">1.88</rating>
<name>Balt-kou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136255.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4706" picture="171561.jpg">Takaguchi Kousuke</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55587" type="appears in" update="2014-02-15">
<rating votes="3">4.28</rating>
<name>Miris Zermuski</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>150275.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="28878" picture="188708.jpg">Fusegawa Kazuhiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55754" type="appears in" update="2013-05-12">
<rating votes="5">3.81</rating>
<name>Mikasa no Haha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136560.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="6012" picture="30714.jpg">Hirose Yuuka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55755" type="appears in" update="2013-05-12">
<rating votes="3">4.45</rating>
<name>Mikasa no Chichi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136561.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2672" picture="188511.jpg">Endou Daichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55756" type="appears in" update="2013-05-12">
<rating votes="4">2.96</rating>
<name>Hahaoya</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136559.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="32916" picture="89530.jpg">Kawasaki Meiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55757" type="appears in" update="2013-05-12">
<rating votes="10">7.21</rating>
<name>Eren Yeager</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136562.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1678" picture="68277.jpg">Kaji Yuuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55758" type="appears in" update="2013-05-12">
<rating votes="14">7.68</rating>
<name>Mikasa Ackerman</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136563.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="443" picture="145927.jpg">Ishikawa Yui</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55903" type="appears in" update="2013-05-18">
<rating votes="4">2.96</rating>
<name>Tom</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136778.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="33630" picture="92065.jpg">Susaki Shigeyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55904" type="appears in" update="2013-05-19">
<rating votes="13">8.57</rating>
<name>Eren Yeager</name>
<gender>none/does not apply</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136779.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1678" picture="68277.jpg">Kaji Yuuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="55905" type="appears in" update="2013-08-04">
<rating votes="5">7.66</rating>
<name>Yoroi no Kyojin</name>
<gender>none/does not apply</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136780.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="55906" type="appears in" update="2013-08-04">
<rating votes="6">7.19</rating>
<name>Chouoogata Kyojin</name>
<gender>none/does not apply</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>136781.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="56372" type="appears in" update="2013-05-30">
<rating votes="2">6.41</rating>
<name>Onna Hokyuu Hei</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>137352.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="32916" picture="89530.jpg">Kawasaki Meiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="56373" type="appears in" update="2013-05-30">
<rating votes="2">4.41</rating>
<name>Hokyuu Hei</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>137351.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="28878" picture="188708.jpg">Fusegawa Kazuhiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="56544" type="appears in" update="2013-06-01">
<rating votes="20">6.46</rating>
<name>Petra Ral</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>137598.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="37377" picture="188508.jpg">Aikawa Natsuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="56545" type="appears in" update="2013-06-01">
<rating votes="10">5.41</rating>
<name>Rico Bretsenska</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>137599.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="36498" picture="188462.jpg">Kaiden Michiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="57223" type="appears in" update="2013-06-16">
<rating votes="4">3.59</rating>
<name>Mitabi Jarnach</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>138604.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="177" picture="170981.jpg">Hoshino Takanori</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="57871" type="appears in" update="2013-07-13">
<rating votes="3">4.46</rating>
<name>Daris Zakkre</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>139995.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="11025" picture="43745.jpg">Tezuka Hideaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="57872" type="appears in" update="2013-07-13">
<rating votes="2">3.46</rating>
<name>Nile Dawk</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>139997.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2002" picture="21307.jpg">Katsu Anri</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="57873" type="appears in" update="2013-07-13">
<rating votes="10">6.02</rating>
<name>Mike Zacharias</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>139996.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="178" picture="16985.jpg">Miyake Kenta</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58029" type="appears in" update="2013-07-20">
<rating votes="8">4.67</rating>
<name>Erdo Gin</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140271.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="375" picture="17221.jpg">Chiba Susumu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58030" type="appears in" update="2013-07-20">
<rating votes="6">4.73</rating>
<name>Oruo Bozad</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140270.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="60" picture="171602.jpg">Kawada Shinji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58031" type="appears in" update="2013-07-20">
<rating votes="6">4.12</rating>
<name>Gunta Schultz</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140272.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="632" picture="18159.jpg">Mito Kouzou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58032" type="appears in" update="2013-07-20">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Sony</name>
<gender>none/does not apply</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140269.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="36642" picture="188475.jpg">Ookuma Kenta</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58033" type="appears in" update="2013-07-20">
<rating votes="3">2.96</rating>
<name>Mobrit</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140273.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="292" picture="68967.jpg">Nishi Rintarou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58034" type="appears in" update="2013-07-20">
<rating votes="4">2.12</rating>
<name>Bean</name>
<gender>none/does not apply</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140274.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="58205" type="appears in" update="2013-07-28">
<rating votes="2">2.29</rating>
<name>Darius Baer Varbrun</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140550.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2365" picture="22143.jpg">Takase Akimitsu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58206" type="appears in" update="2013-07-28">
<rating votes="4">4.38</rating>
<name>Dita Ness</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140549.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="377" picture="17223.jpg">Sakaguchi Kouichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58219" type="appears in" update="2013-07-28">
<rating votes="2">2.91</rating>
<name>Kenpei Dan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140551.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="33630" picture="92065.jpg">Susaki Shigeyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58220" type="appears in" update="2013-07-28">
<rating votes="2">2.73</rating>
<name>Onna Heishi</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140552.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="38115" picture="139630.jpg">Maruyama Yuka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58221" type="appears in" update="2013-07-28">
<rating votes="2">2.11</rating>
<name>Imouto</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140553.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="38169" picture="139881.jpg">Kobori Miyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="58452" type="appears in" update="2013-08-04">
<rating votes="11">6.90</rating>
<name>Megata no Kyojin</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140875.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="58453" type="appears in" update="2013-08-04">
<rating votes="5">2.68</rating>
<name>Luke Sys</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>140876.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="38116" picture="188464.jpg">Kitada Masamichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59440" type="appears in" update="2015-08-17">
<rating votes="3">3.23</rating>
<name>Nanaba</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142404.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1735" picture="31933.jpg">Shimoda Asami</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59552" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="4">5.37</rating>
<name>Erdo Koibito</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142772.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="38578" picture="143891.jpg">Kirishima Yuka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59553" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="2">2.29</rating>
<name>Erdo Haha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142773.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="36498" picture="188462.jpg">Kaiden Michiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59554" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Oruo Haha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142774.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4762" picture="201584.jpg">Kodaira Yuuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59555" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Oruo Chichi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142775.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="10899" picture="46179.jpg">Nishina Youhei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59556" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="3">2.24</rating>
<name>Gunta Haha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142777.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="5960" picture="188720.jpg">Ootori Yoshino</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59557" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Gunta Sofu</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142776.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="20532" picture="188517.jpg">Takubo Shuuhei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59558" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="2">3.69</rating>
<name>Dita</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142771.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="32615" picture="87674.jpg">Sasaki Yoshihito</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59559" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Petra Chichi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142780.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3185" picture="171529.jpg">Terasoma Masaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59560" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="1">2.96</rating>
<name>Peer</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142779.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2672" picture="188511.jpg">Endou Daichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59561" type="appears in" update="2013-09-09">
<rating votes="2">1.91</rating>
<name>Juergen</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>142778.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="28878" picture="188708.jpg">Fusegawa Kazuhiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59881" type="appears in" update="2013-09-16">
<rating votes="2">1.73</rating>
<name>Annie no Chichi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>143239.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="339" picture="79312.jpg">Ishizuka Unshou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59882" type="appears in" update="2013-09-16">
<rating votes="3">2.24</rating>
<name>Wall Kyou Shinja no Otoko</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>143238.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="28878" picture="188708.jpg">Fusegawa Kazuhiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59883" type="appears in" update="2014-02-15">
<rating votes="2">3.69</rating>
<name>Denis Ivinger</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>150273.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="59884" type="appears in" update="2013-09-16">
<rating votes="5">4.63</rating>
<name>Hitch</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>143237.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="192" picture="41287.jpg">Watanabe Akeno</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59885" type="appears in" update="2014-02-15">
<rating votes="2">2.29</rating>
<name>Boris Firna</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>150271.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="31811" picture="85614.jpg">Karasuma Yuuichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="59886" type="appears in" update="2013-09-16">
<rating votes="3">3.98</rating>
<name>Marlo Freudenberg</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>143240.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="45" picture="44970.jpg">Sugita Tomokazu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="60039" type="appears in" update="2013-09-24">
<rating votes="3">2.24</rating>
<name>Waltz</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<seiyuu id="17705" picture="188509.jpg">Asari Ryouta</seiyuu>
</character>
</characters>
<episodes>
<episode id="147561" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="4">T1</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">CM15s</title>
</episode>
<episode id="148625" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">4</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-04-28</airdate>
<rating votes="38">7.01</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">解散式の夜 人類の再起②</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Night of the Graduation Ceremony: Humanity Rises Again (2)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Die Nacht der Auflösung - Die Wiederherstellung der Menschheit (Teil 2)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Le soir de la cérémonie de fin d`entraînement ~Le réveil de l`humanité~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kaisanshiki no Yoru: Jinrui no Saiki (2)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="148626" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">3</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-04-21</airdate>
<rating votes="36">5.29</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">絶望の中で鈍く光る 人類の再起①</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Dim Light in the Darkness of Despair: Humanity Rises Again (1)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Ein trübes Licht in der Verzweiflung - Die Wiederherstellung der Menschheit (Teil 1)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Une faible étincelle dans le désespoir ~Le réveil de l`humanité~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Zetsubou no Naka de Nibuku Hikaru: Jinrui no Saiki (1)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="148627" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">2</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-04-14</airdate>
<rating votes="40">6.04</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">その日 シガンシナ陥落②</title>
<title xml:lang="en">That Day: The Fall of Zhiganshina (2)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Dieser Tag - Der Niedergang von Shiganshina (Teil 2)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Ce jour-là ~2) La chute de Shiganshina~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Sono Hi: Zhiganshina Kanraku (2)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="148628" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">1</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-04-07</airdate>
<rating votes="55">7.80</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">二千年後の君へ シガンシナ陥落①</title>
<title xml:lang="en">To You, 2000 Years in the Future: The Fall of Zhiganshina (1)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">An euch in 2000 Jahren - Der Niedergang von Shiganshina (Teil 1)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">À toi qui vis 2000 ans plus tard</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Nisen-nengo no Kimi e: Shiganshina Kanraku (1)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="148933" update="2013-04-07">
<epno type="3">C1</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2013-04-07</airdate>
<rating votes="5">7.90</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Opening 1a</title>
</episode>
<episode id="149625" update="2013-07-13">
<epno type="3">C4</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2013-04-14</airdate>
<rating votes="2">7.21</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 1</title>
</episode>
<episode id="149838" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">7</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-05-19</airdate>
<rating votes="38">8.45</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">小さな刃 トロスト区攻防戦③</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Small Blade: The Battle for Trost (3)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Die kleine Klinge - Die Schlacht von Trost (Teil 3)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Courte lame ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chiisana Yaiba: Trost-ku Koubousen (3)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="149839" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">6</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-05-12</airdate>
<rating votes="37">6.58</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">少女が見た世界 トロスト区攻防戦②</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The World the Girl Saw: Battle for Trost (2)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Die Welt die Sie sah - Die Schlacht von Trost (Teil 2)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Une petite lame ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Shoujo ga Mita Sekai: Trost-ku Koubousen (2)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="149840" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">5</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-05-05</airdate>
<rating votes="39">8.39</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">初陣 トロスト区攻防戦①</title>
<title xml:lang="en">First Battle: Battle of Trost (1)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Erste Schlacht - Die Schlacht von Trost (Teil 1)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Première bataille ~La lutte pour le district Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Uijin: Trost-ku Koubousen (1)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="150058" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">8</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-05-26</airdate>
<rating votes="36">9.06</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">心臓の鼓動が聞こえる トロスト区攻防戦④</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Hearing the Heartbeat: The Battle for Trost (4)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Ich kann ein Herz schlagen hören - Die Schlacht von Trost (Teil 4)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">J`entends les battements de ton cœur ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Shinzou no Kodou ga Kikoeru: Trost-ku Koubousen (4)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="150356" update="2013-05-05">
<epno type="3">C2</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2013-04-28</airdate>
<rating votes="2">6.54</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Opening 1b</title>
</episode>
<episode id="150610" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">12</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-06-23</airdate>
<rating votes="31">4.65</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">傷 トロスト区攻防戦⑧</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Wound: The Battle for Trost (8)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Blessure ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kizu: Trost-ku Koubousen (8)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="150611" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">11</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-06-16</airdate>
<rating votes="33">5.72</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">偶像 トロスト区攻防戦⑦</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Icon: The Battle for Trost (7)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Idole ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Guuzou: Trost-ku Koubousen (7)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="150612" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">10</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-06-09</airdate>
<rating votes="34">5.20</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">応える トロスト区攻防戦⑥</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Response: The Battle for Trost (6)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Répondre ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kotaeru: Trost-ku Koubousen (6)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="150613" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">9</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-06-02</airdate>
<rating votes="33">7.74</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">左腕の行方 トロスト区攻防戦⑤</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Where the Left Arm Went: The Battle for Trost (5)</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Wo ist der linke Arm ? - Die Schlacht von Trost (Teil 5)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Qu`est-il advenu du bras gauche ? ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Hidari Ude no Yukue: Trost-ku Koubousen (5)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="151173" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">16</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-07-28</airdate>
<rating votes="25">6.09</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">今, 何をすべきか 反撃前夜③</title>
<title xml:lang="en">What Should Be Done: Night Before the Counteroffensive (3)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Ce qu`il faut faire maintenant ~La veille de la contre-attaque~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Ima, Nani o Subeki ka: Hangeki Zen`ya (3)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="151174" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">15</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-07-21</airdate>
<rating votes="28">4.80</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">特別作戦班 反撃前夜②</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Special Ops Squad: Night Before the Counteroffensive (2)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Unité d`intervention ~La veille de la contre-attaque~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tokubetsu Sakusen-han: Hangeki Zen`ya (2)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="151175" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">14</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-07-14</airdate>
<rating votes="33">4.78</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">まだ目を見れない 反撃前夜①</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Still Can`t See: Night Before the Counteroffensive (1)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">On ne peut pas le regarder dans les yeux ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Mada Me o Mirenai: Hangeki Zen`ya (1)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="151176" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">13</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-06-30</airdate>
<rating votes="34">6.07</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">原初的欲求 トロスト区攻防戦⑨</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Primal Desires: The Battle for Trost (9)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Désir primitif ~La lutte pour le district de Trost~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Genshoteki Yokkyuu: Trost-ku Koubousen (9)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="151521" recap="true" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="2">S1</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-07-07</airdate>
<rating votes="9">2.16</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">あの日から</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Since That Day</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Depuis l`autre jour</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Ano Hi kara</title>
</episode>
<episode id="151911" update="2013-07-13">
<epno type="3">C5</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2013-07-14</airdate>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 2</title>
</episode>
<episode id="151912" update="2013-07-13">
<epno type="3">C3</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2013-07-14</airdate>
<rating votes="2">8.73</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Opening 2</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152031" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">20</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-08-25</airdate>
<rating votes="25">7.79</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">エルヴィン・スミス 第57回壁外調査④</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Erwin Smith: 57th Expedition Beyond the Walls (4)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Erwin Smith ~La 57e expédition extra-muros~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Erwin Smith: Dai 57 Kai Hekigai Chousa (4)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152032" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">19</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-08-18</airdate>
<rating votes="25">6.38</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">噛みつく 第57回壁外調査③</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Bite: 57th Expedition Beyond the Walls (3)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Morsure: La 57e expédition extra-muros</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kamitsuku: Dai 57 Kai Hekigai Chousa (3)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152033" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">18</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-08-11</airdate>
<rating votes="28">7.94</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">巨大樹の森 第57回壁外調査②</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Forest of Giant Trees: 57th Expedition Beyond the Walls (2)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">La forêt des arbres géants: La 57e expédition extra-muros</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kyodaiju no Mori: Dai 57 Kai Hekigai Chousa (2)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152034" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">17</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-08-04</airdate>
<rating votes="27">7.90</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">女型の巨人 第57回壁外調査①</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Female Titan: 57th Expedition Beyond the Walls (1)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Le titan féminin ~ La 57e expédition extra-muros ~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Megata no Kyojin: Dai 57 Kai Hekigai Chousa (1)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152188" update="2013-07-29">
<epno type="2">S2</epno>
<length>5</length>
<airdate>2013-07-17</airdate>
<rating votes="1">2.24</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 1</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152566" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">24</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-09-22</airdate>
<rating votes="24">9.04</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">慈悲 ストヘス区急襲②</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Mercy: Raid on Stohess District (2)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Pitié ~Attaque surprise au district de Stohess~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Jihi: Stohess-ku Kyuushuu (2)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152567" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">23</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-09-15</airdate>
<rating votes="25">6.75</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">微笑み ストヘス区急襲①</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Smile: Raid on Stohess District (1)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Sourire ~Attaque surprise au district de Stohess~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Hohoemi: Stohess-ku Kyuushuu (1)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152568" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">22</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-09-08</airdate>
<rating votes="26">7.48</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">敗者達 第57回壁外調査⑥</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Defeated: 57th Expedition Beyond the Walls (6)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Les vaincus ~La 57e expédition extra-muros~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Haisha-tachi: Dai 57 Kai Hekigai Chousa (6)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152569" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">21</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-09-01</airdate>
<rating votes="30">9.39</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">鉄槌 第57回壁外調査⑤</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Crushing Blow: 57th Expedition Beyond the Walls (5)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Coup dur ~La 57e expédition extra-muros~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tettsui: Dai 57 Kai Hekigai Chousa (5)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="152789" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">25</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2013-09-28</airdate>
<rating votes="22">9.04</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">壁 ストヘス区急襲③</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Wall: Raid on Stohess District (3)</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">Mur ~Attaque surprise au district de Stohess~</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kabe: Stohess-ku Kyuushuu (3)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="153241" update="2013-08-30">
<epno type="2">S3</epno>
<length>7</length>
<airdate>2013-08-21</airdate>
<rating votes="1">2.24</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団 2</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 2</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan 2</title>
</episode>
<episode id="154373" update="2013-12-20">
<epno type="2">S4</epno>
<length>15</length>
<airdate>2013-09-18</airdate>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団 3</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 3</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan 3</title>
</episode>
<episode id="154407" update="2013-09-28">
<epno type="3">C6</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2013-09-28</airdate>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 3</title>
</episode>
<episode id="156773" update="2013-12-20">
<epno type="2">S5</epno>
<length>15</length>
<airdate>2013-10-16</airdate>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団 4</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 4</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan 4</title>
</episode>
<episode id="157054" update="2014-01-05">
<epno type="2">S8</epno>
<length>15</length>
<airdate>2014-01-15</airdate>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団 7</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 7</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan 7</title>
</episode>
<episode id="157055" update="2014-06-18">
<epno type="2">S7</epno>
<length>15</length>
<airdate>2013-12-18</airdate>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団 6</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 6</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan 6</title>
</episode>
<episode id="157056" update="2014-06-18">
<epno type="2">S6</epno>
<length>15</length>
<airdate>2013-11-20</airdate>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団 5</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 5</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan 5</title>
</episode>
<episode id="160363" update="2014-06-05">
<epno type="2">S10</epno>
<length>10</length>
<airdate>2014-03-19</airdate>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団 9</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 9</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan 9</title>
</episode>
<episode id="160364" update="2014-06-05">
<epno type="2">S9</epno>
<length>10</length>
<airdate>2014-02-19</airdate>
<title xml:lang="ja">ちみキャラ劇場 とんでけ! 訓練兵団 8</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Picture Drama 8</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chimi Chara Gekijou: Tondeke! Kunren Heidan 8</title>
</episode>
<episode id="174967" update="2016-02-10">
<epno type="2">S13</epno>
<length>4</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Eyecatch Gallery</title>
</episode>
<episode id="174968" update="2016-02-10">
<epno type="2">S12</epno>
<length>20</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Attack on Titan at Anime Expo</title>
</episode>
<episode id="174969" update="2016-02-10">
<epno type="2">S11</epno>
<length>55</length>
<title xml:lang="en">The Making of Attack on Titan</title>
</episode>
</episodes>
</anime>
