<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><anime id="5787" restricted="false">
<type>TV Series</type>
<episodecount>13</episodecount>
<startdate>2008-07-08</startdate>
<enddate>2008-09-30</enddate>
<titles>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="main">Natsume Yuujinchou</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="synonym">Natsume`s Friend Book</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="synonym">Natsume</title>
<title xml:lang="de" type="synonym">Pakt der Yokai</title>
<title xml:lang="ru" type="synonym">Тетрадь дружбы Нацумэ</title>
<title xml:lang="el" type="synonym">Το "βιβλίο των φίλων" του Νατσούμε</title>
<title xml:lang="vi" type="synonym">Quyển sổ người bạn</title>
<title xml:lang="fa" type="synonym">کتابِ دوستان ناتسومه</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">nyc</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">ny</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">ny1</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">Natsume 1</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="official">夏目友人帳</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="official">Natsume`s Book of Friends</title>
<title xml:lang="fr" type="official">Le Pacte des Yōkai</title>
<title xml:lang="th" type="official">นัตสึเมะกับบันทึกพิศวง</title>
<title xml:lang="zh-Hans" type="official">夏目友人帐</title>
</titles>
<relatedanime>
<anime id="6185" type="Sequel">Zoku Natsume Yuujinchou</anime>
<anime id="10447" type="Side Story">Natsume Yuujinchou: Itsuka Yuki no Hi ni</anime>
</relatedanime>
<similaranime>
<anime id="3433" approval="257" total="280">Mushishi</anime>
<anime id="8289" approval="99" total="100">Hotarubi no Mori e</anime>
<anime id="4032" approval="95" total="110">xxxHOLiC</anime>
<anime id="3195" approval="59" total="75">Kamichu!</anime>
<anime id="5052" approval="42" total="48">Mokke</anime>
<anime id="9836" approval="32" total="36">Gingitsune</anime>
<anime id="291" approval="28" total="41">Hanada Shounen-shi</anime>
<anime id="11924" approval="26" total="28">Fukigen na Mononokean</anime>
<anime id="2837" approval="12" total="24">Zettai Shounen</anime>
<anime id="11469" approval="6" total="13">Flying Witch</anime>
<anime id="8270" approval="6" total="13">Momo e no Tegami</anime>
<anime id="11053" approval="6" total="12">Ushio to Tora (2015)</anime>
<anime id="7404" approval="4" total="11">Nurarihyon no Mago</anime>
<anime id="34" approval="3" total="11">Fruits Basket</anime>
<anime id="3614" approval="3" total="3">Amefurikozou</anime>
<anime id="6772" approval="1" total="8">Tegami Bachi</anime>
</similaranime>
<recommendations total="28">
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="305556">Well-paced and nuanced so far!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="100018">Great series! :)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very heartwarming and funny...not too serious though.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="278512">This is a very interesting anime somewhat reminiscent of Mushishi (which is pretty rare to say the least)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="312138">very relaxing, subtle and quite humoristic anime.&lt;br /&gt;don`t be deceived by its mellow intro :P</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="283697">great story , a must see!!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="88600">watch this for a night time anime</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="122157">great storyline...simple... but yet sometimes it makes you wonder... what you want in life...</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="254003">One of the best anime of this genre</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="259124">Its really really good "soft" anime. One of the best series of the year for me. It works on me kind like Aria i mean it leaves same expresion tho i like the genere here coz i love ayakashi xD</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="232807">Good anime. Cute and touching too</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="563093">There`s no better medicine than a glass of wine and Natsume Yuujinchou after a hard day at work. This bittersweet, affectionate beauty—so rarely done well in anime—soothes the mind unlike anything else.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="132589">This anime was very good. It was very laid back and easy-going. The story moves a bit slow but it isn`t boring. Definately worth a watch because it`s short and sweet. Continue if you`d like :)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="511686">Based on the Japanese tradition about spirits and Shinto Gods ( religion which has many similarities to ancient Greek religion and other ancient beliefs, basically connected to the  worship of Nature). This anime finds a unique way to speak about loneliness, love,  kindness and tolerance of the different.</recommendation>
</recommendations>
<url>http://www.natsume-anime.jp/</url>
<creators>
<name id="982" type="Animation Work">Brain`s Base</name>
<name id="7033" type="Character Design">Takada Akira</name>
<name id="4359" type="Direction">Oomori Takahiro</name>
<name id="7033" type="Chief Animation Direction">Takada Akira</name>
<name id="6041" type="Chief Animation Direction">Yamada Tatsuo</name>
<name id="2323" type="Series Composition">Kanemaki Ken`ichi</name>
<name id="783" type="Work">NAS</name>
<name id="3542" type="Original Work">Midorikawa Yuki</name>
<name id="6006" type="Music">Yoshimori Makoto</name>
</creators>
<description>http://anidb.net/ch1806 [Natsume Takashi] has the ability to see spirits, which he has long kept secret. However, once he inherits a strange book that belonged to his deceased grandmother, http://anidb.net/ch1808 [Reiko], he discovers the reason why spirits surround him. Containing the names of these spirits, a binding contract was formed between the spirits and the owner of the book. Now, Natsume is determined to free the spirits and dissolve the contracts. With the help of a spirit cat, his days are filled trying to return the names to these spirits.
Source: ANN</description>
<ratings>
<permanent count="4073">8.12</permanent>
<temporary count="4113">8.25</temporary>
<review count="3">7.33</review>
</ratings>
<picture>8997.jpg</picture>
<resources>
<resource type="1">
<externalentity>
<identifier>9419</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="2">
<externalentity>
<identifier>4081</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="3">
<externalentity>
<identifier>4285</identifier>
<identifier>ztrcdh</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="4">
<externalentity>
<url>http://www.natsume-anime.jp/</url>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="6">
<externalentity>
<identifier>Natsume's_Book_of_Friends</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="7">
<externalentity>
<identifier>夏目友人帳</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="8">
<externalentity>
<identifier>1414</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="9">
<externalentity>
<identifier>330645</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="10">
<externalentity>
<identifier>10044</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="11">
<externalentity>
<identifier>mediadb/media/2179</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="15">
<externalentity>
<identifier>2008/natsume</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>natsume-yujin-cho</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
<tags>
<tag id="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>meta tags</name>
<description>These tags are used for maintenance.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1077" parentid="2606" infobox="true" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-04">
<name>shoujo</name>
<description>In the context of manga and associated media, shoujo, literally meaning "girl", refers to a female audience roughly between the ages of 10 and 18.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1835" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-12-31">
<name>animal sidekick</name>
<description>Every mahou shoujo anime needs them, the cute little critters that are supposed to help the protagonists but in reality are nothing but useless bystanders most often abused for gags. Kids love them but they can also often turn into an annoyance.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2043" parentid="2869" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-12-07">
<name>high school</name>
<description>A secondary school that usually contains grades 10 through 12 in Japan, or 9 through 12 in America.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2094" parentid="2849" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-10-25">
<name>magic</name>
<description>Magic is the art of purportedly manipulating aspects of reality either by supernatural means or through knowledge of unknown occult laws.</description>
<picurl>178878.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2253" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-09-01">
<name>kitsune</name>
<description>Kitsune is the Japanese word for fox, which are a common subject of Japanese folklore. This term in English specifically refers to them in this context.
Stories depict them as intelligent beings and as possessing magical abilities that increase with their age and wisdom. Foremost among these is the ability to assume human form.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2302" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2011-04-02">
<name>helpful</name>
</tag>
<tag id="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-28">
<name>dynamic</name>
<description>Some of the central structural elements in anime are: 
Plot Continuity 
How does the plot or several plots unfold. Are they a strictly linear retelling of one big continuing story, a serial, possibly with several side stories, or is the content chopped into a set of unconnected episodes, only sharing the same setting and characters?
Stereotype Characters
Then there is the question of the character set presentation. Is it completely original, or is it your usual stereotypical character cast. Both choices have their merit, for example it would not really make much sense to reinvent the wheel for a harem anime. Fans of that genre come to expect their favourite stereotype protagonists.
Plot Twists
Finally there is the question of how complex the plot / the story unfolds. Are there side-plots that merge into the main plot leading to unexpected plot twists, or is the anime quite predictable? The latter would not be appropriate for detective stories. In harem anime on the other hand a foreseeable outcome is actually something the fans will come to expect.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2606" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-18">
<name>target audience</name>
<description>Anime, like everything else in the modern world, is targeted towards specific audiences, both implicitly by the creators and overtly by the marketing. While categories are associated with specific sex and age groups, this is not a bar on the anime being enjoyed by people who don`t fit into that band; not only do crossover titles exist, but the categories also have a considerable following outside their main demographic, and a person might as well enjoy anime from all categories. Still, does not invalidate the usefulness of marking a title as one of the categories; the same themes will likely be treated differently in anime geared for different audiences. Only one should not jump the gun and assume that a title will be more or less serious or present content in this or that way due to its target audience, or conversely assume the target audience on the content and its presentation alone. As such, the audience categories help form a broad impression of how a title might work with the announced themes, but offer little to no in-depth information about specific content or its treatment.
The audience categories originate from manga magazines, which group titles of a same intended audience into a magazine that is advertised as belonging to that category, and so manga-based anime will have the category from their parent work. As for anime based on other works, the audience is often debatable, but comparing information such as time slot to the manga-based anime generally helps figure out the most likely possibility.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-29">
<name>themes</name>
<description>Themes describe the very central elements important to the anime stories. They set the backdrop against which the protagonists must face their challenges. Be it School Life, present Daily Life, Military action, Cyberpunk, Law and Order detective work, Sports, or the Underworld. These are only but a few of the more typical backgrounds for anime plots. Add to that a Conspiracy setting with a possible tragic outcome, the Themes span most of the imaginable subject matter relevant to anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2609" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-22">
<name>original work</name>
<description>What the anime is based on! Mostly of academic interest, but a useful bit of info, hinting at the possible depth of story.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-22">
<name>setting</name>
<description>The setting describes in what time and place an anime takes place. To a certain extent it describes what you can expect from the world in the anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-08">
<name>elements</name>
<description>Next to Themes setting the backdrop for the protagonists in anime, there are the more detailed plot Elements that centre on character interactions: "What do characters do to each other or what is done to them?". Is it violent Action, an awe-inspiring Adventure in a foreign place, the gripping life of a Detective, a slapstick Comedy, an Ecchi Harem anime, a SciFi epic, or some Fantasy travelling adventure?</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2612" parentid="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>time</name>
<description>This placeholder lists different epochs in human history and more vague but important timelines such as the future, the present and the past.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2613" parentid="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>place</name>
<description>The places the anime can take place in. Includes more specific places such as a country on Earth, as well as more general places such as a dystopia or a mirror world.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2624" parentid="2612" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-02-20">
<name>present</name>
<description>Somewhere between past and future.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2630" parentid="2613" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-13">
<name>Earth</name>
<description>The Earth is the third planet from the Sun, and the densest and fifth-largest of the eight planets in the Solar System. It is in effect a ball of hot mud, but on the surface it`s cold enough, so most of us live on it (or are supposed to). It is circa 4.5 billion years old, and, unless we humans succeed in destroying it over the next couple of centuries, it is expected to last for quite another while, though the changes in the Sun`s emissions due to its aging will likely cause the extinction of everything; the species of earthlings are guaranteed to die, even if we fail to kill them -- unless, of course, we find ourselves another planet and figure out a way to take everything there. Our little planet on a corner of this galaxy may mean nothing in the grand scheme of things, but to its inhabitants it is their home, so, as a species, we cherish it dearly, to the point many cultures even to this day deify it. Being the home to the human civilizations, the Earth is the main setting of most fiction, be it anime or otherwise, but not only are many titles set in other places, such as unrelated fantasy worlds, in a considerable number of fictional titles the Earth is actually destroyed by aggressive alien invaders.</description>
<picurl>126792.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2646" parentid="2849" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-24">
<name>demon</name>
<description>In Western lore, demons are often described as minions from Hell, generally known to attack humans and feast on their flesh or possess the bodies of those with weak souls. In Eastern lore, on the other hand, they are generally supernatural, often but not always malevolent beings who can be more mischievous than actually evil, or simply supernatural spirits of no specific alignment.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2648" parentid="2849" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-11-04">
<name>contemporary fantasy</name>
<description>Contemporary fantasy, also known as modern fantasy or indigenous fantasy, is a sub-genre of fantasy, set in the present day. It is perhaps most popular for its sub-genre, urban fantasy.
These terms are used to describe stories set in the putative real world (often referred to as consensus reality) in contemporary times, in which magic and magical creatures exist, either living in the interstices of our world or leaking over from alternate worlds. It thus has much in common with, and sometimes overlaps with secret history; a work of fantasy in which the magic could not remain secret or does not have any known relationship to known history would not fit into this subgenre. Occasionally certain contemporary fantasy novels will make reference to pop culture.
Novels in which modern characters travel into alternate worlds, and all the magical action takes place there (except for the portal required to transport them), are not considered contemporary fantasy. Thus, C.S. Lewis`s The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe, where all fantasy events take place in the land of Narnia which is reached via a magic wardrobe, would not count as contemporary fantasy; on the other hand, the part of The Magician`s Nephew, where the Empress Jadis gets to London, tries to take over the Earth and clashes with police and a crowd of cockneys, would qualify as such.
Contemporary fantasy is also to be distinguished from horror fiction, which also often has contemporary settings. When encountering magical events and creatures, the protagonist of a horror novel is horrified, while the protagonist of a fantasy novel (contemporary or otherwise) is filled with a sense of joy and wonder. Horrifying events may happen, but the fundamental distinction is vital.
In his preface to That Hideous Strength, one of the earlier works falling within this sub-genre, C.S. Lewis explained why, when writing a tale about "magicians, devils, pantomime animals and planetary angels", he chose to start it with a detailed depiction of narrow-minded academic politics at a provincial English university and the schemes of crooked real estate developers: "I am following the traditional fairy-tale. We do not always notice its method, because the cottages, castles, woodcutters and petty kings with which a fairy tale opens have become for us as remote as the witches and ogres to which it proceeds. But they were not remote at all to the men who first made and enjoyed the tales". The same is true for many of the later works in the genre, which often begin with a seemingly normal scene of modern daily life to then disclose supernatural and magical beings and events hidden behind the scenes.
Source: wiki</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2672" parentid="2834" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-05-31">
<name>Japan</name>
<description>Last stronghold for humanity. If Tokyo falls, it`s all over. Tokyo Tower will undoubtedly fall anyway.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2773" parentid="2094" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-01-18">
<name>magic circles</name>
<description>A magic circle is circle or sphere of space marked out by practitioners of many branches of ritual magic. It may be marked physically, drawn in salt or chalk, for example, or merely visualised.
Traditionally, circles have been used by ritual magicians to form a protective barrier between themselves and what they summoned. Nowadays, circles often have the more benign function of containing and concentrating the energy raised during a ritual. Circles can also be used as barriers for non-magical work such as meditation.
Generally, as with most magical practices, an incantation is recited stating the purpose and nature of the circle, often repeating an assortment of divine and angelic names.
Source: wiki</description>
<picurl>32800.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2790" parentid="2605" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-01-17">
<name>plot continuity</name>
<description>Consistency of the characteristics of persons, plot, objects, places and events seen by the viewer.
A single linear focused plot is highly continuous.
A truly random plot is highly discontinuous.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2798" parentid="2609" infobox="true" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-07">
<name>manga</name>
<description>Manga is the lifeblood that drives the anime industry. Everything and its mother is based on manga. However! There are exceptions where the manga was not the basis for the anime.
It`s common practice to make manga adaptations of many popular anime, there`s a manga based on Evangelion, and two (one shounen and one shoujo) based on each of Escaflowne and Mahou Tsukai Tai. Also it`s quite common to release manga and anime versions of a story in parallel, for instance Nadesico and Shoujo Kakumei Utena. There are also cases where an anime continues in a manga, as in the case of Angel Beats! and Angel Beats: Heaven`s Door, or reverse.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2834" parentid="2630" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-10-04">
<name>Asia</name>
<description>Asia is Earth`s largest and most populous continent, located primarily in the eastern and northern hemispheres and sharing the continental landmass of Eurasia with the continent of Europe. Asia covers an area of 44,579,000 square kilometers, about 30% of Earth`s total land area and 8.7% of the Earth`s total surface area. The continent, which has long been home to the majority of the human population, was the site of many of the first civilizations. Asia is notable for not only its overall large size and population, but also dense and large settlements as well as vast barely populated regions within the continent of 4.4 billion people.
Source: Wikipedia</description>
<picurl>192245.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2849" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2005-05-07">
<name>fantasy</name>
<description>Fantasy is a genre of fiction that uses magic and other supernatural phenomena as a primary element of plot, theme, or setting. Many works within the genre take place in fictional worlds where magic is common. Fantasy is generally distinguished from science fiction and horror by the expectation that it steers clear of (pseudo-)scientific and macabre themes, respectively, though there is a great deal of overlap between the three (which are subgenres of speculative fiction).
In popular culture, the genre of fantasy is dominated by its medievalist form, especially since the worldwide success of The Lord of the Rings books by J. R. R. Tolkien. In its broadest sense however, fantasy comprises works by many writers, artists, filmmakers, and musicians, from ancient myths and legends to many recent works embraced by a wide audience today.
Fantasy is a vibrant area of academic study in a number of disciplines (English, cultural studies, comparative literature, history, medieval studies). Work in this area ranges widely, from the structuralist theory of Tzvetan Todorov, which emphasizes the fantastic as a liminal space, to work on the connections (political, historical, literary) between medievalism and popular culture
Source: Wiki</description>
<picurl>68768.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2853" parentid="2611" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-02-13">
<name>comedy</name>
<description>Anime whose central struggle causes hilarious results. These stories are built upon funny characters, situations and events. A comedy anime is laced with humour and sets out to provoke laughter from the audience.
Japanese humour can be a bit strange to westerners, so if you`re new to this type of humour, just bear with it; it`ll most likely grow on you if you`re a fan of other kinds of comedy.</description>
<picurl>198104.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2862" parentid="2607" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-11">
<name>friendship</name>
<description>The feeling of trust, kindness, and friendship between a group of high school students for example, is a central theme of this anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2864" parentid="2607" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-12-29">
<name>daily life</name>
<description>The antics of the protagonists do not take place in some exotic setting or time, but in everyday life. When not "at the job" this means getting up in the morning, making meals, house cleaning, going shopping or out to eat, visiting the bath house or spa, leisure activities in the spare time, etc. The time "on the job" for students is School Life, for others working in their profession. Daily Life is basically a synonym for everything normal, repetitive, and trivial happening to your average person.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2865" parentid="6148" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-09-16">
<name>summer festival</name>
<description>The summer festival is used to show off the female protagonists in traditional Japanese clothing — the yukata — a casual form of kimono.
The festivities include food stalls (cotton candy, candy apples, choco bananas, taiyaki), various games (scoop goldfishes), and a fireworks display.</description>
<picurl>161023.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2869" parentid="2607" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-23">
<name>school life</name>
<description>Since a large part of the anime audience still takes part in school life or is visiting college, it is only natural to choose a setting the audience can identify with, be it elementary, middle, or high school. For the older viewers a college setting with more mature real-life problems is appropriate. And since clubs take up so much time in the lives of students, these are obviously also important.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2876" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-08">
<name>religion</name>
<description>Religion is a collection of belief systems, cultural systems, and worldviews that relate humanity to spirituality and, sometimes, to moral values. Many religions have narratives, symbols, traditions and sacred histories that are intended to give meaning to life or to explain the origin of life or the universe. They tend to derive morality, ethics, religious laws or a preferred lifestyle from their ideas about the cosmos and human nature.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2879" parentid="2607" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-02-27">
<name>alcohol</name>
<description>Alcohol (or more scientifically, ethanol), is one of the world`s oldest psychoactive substances. It is traditionally found in the form of a beverage such as beer, wine, or liquor, although in some contexts it can be inhaled to produce similar or intoxication, and some people prefer another way of consuming beverage-form alcohol.
Alcoholic beverages are many and varied, due to production methods (fermentation or distillation), source materials (grains, fruits, vegetables, other plants), added substances such as flavorings, and many more ways of defining different forms of alcoholic beverages.
Alcoholic beverages are divided into three general classes: beers, wines, and spirits. They are legally consumed in most countries, and over 100 countries have laws regulating their production, sale, and consumption. In particular, such laws specify the minimum age at which a person may legally buy or drink them. This minimum age varies between 16 and 25 years, depending upon the country and the type of drink. Most nations set it at 18 years of age.</description>
<picurl>70749.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-12-04">
<name>unsorted</name>
<description>a bunch of tags that still need to be either deleted or moved into proper places.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3040" parentid="6230" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-08-16">
<name>male protagonist</name>
<description>These anime have a male protagonist.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3148" parentid="6247" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-10-14">
<name>open-ended</name>
<description>The ending of this anime is left to the viewers imagination. There are no clear hints at a definite story outcome, just several possibilities are presented.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3328" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false">
<name>melancholic</name>
</tag>
<tag id="3502" parentid="6232" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2012-04-14">
<name>troubled male lead</name>
<description>The male lead character will be in some sort of trouble within himself or only he is able to know of the trouble.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3597" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2013-02-26">
<name>mythology</name>
<description>The anime gets inspirations from many forms of mythologies (either Greek, Egyptian, Nord, etc.) to form its story and setting.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3869" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-04-12">
<name>mono no aware</name>
<description>Literally "the pathos of things", also translated as "an empathy toward things," or "a sensitivity of ephemera"; a Japanese term used to describe the awareness of the transience of things and a gentle sadness (or wistfulness) at their passing.
Also frequently been translated as "the `ahh-ness` of things".</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3876" parentid="3597" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-21">
<name>folklore</name>
<description>Folklore, or simply Lore, are the traditions of a culture, subculture, or group, in the form of legends, music, proverbs, jokes, popular beliefs, fairy tales, stories, tall tales and customs. In usage, there is a continuum between folklore and mythology.
Folklore is generally divided into four areas of study: physical artifacts, transmissible entities and stories, culture and technologies, and behaviors and rituals.
[From Wikipedia]</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4048" parentid="3597" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-17">
<name>Japanese mythology</name>
<description>Japanese mythology is a system of beliefs that embraces Shinto and Buddhist traditions as well as agriculture-based folk religion. The Shinto pantheon alone consists of an uncountable number of kami (Japanese for "gods" or "spirits").
(Source: Wikipedia)</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4312" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2010-04-23">
<name>bitter-sweet</name>
<description>An anime that is, at the same time, bitter and sweet. In other words, it expresses the conflicting concepts of pain and pleasure through emotions such as melancholy. Said emotions can be either sad or joyful, and oftentimes both sad and joyful at once.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4498" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-03-20">
<name>heart-warming</name>
<description>The story and its characters give off good vibes — includes elevated feelings of affection such as tenderness, sympathy and love, all in one package.
The kind of anime which leaves you with a warm feeling inside and you can not stop smiling while watching it.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4564" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2011-06-01">
<name>spirits</name>
<description>Spirits will appear throughout this anime. These will often be depicted as small orbs of glowing light, or transparent images of the deceased.
Not to be mistaken with "I see dead people", these spirits will usually appear at the location of their departure when the characters have gotten close to the truth surrounding their death. Or as plot element, when a spirit will often stay close to a character as a sort of "Guardian Angel". Although they are never actually seen, their presence is sometimes felt.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5585" parentid="2607" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-01-29">
<name>curse</name>
<description>A "curse" in this manner depicts an adversity placed upon a person or object by a supernatural power often represented by unique designs and symbols found on the inflicted. While not all curses have negative effects, the majority are meant to remain forever hexing to the receiving victim`s soul.
A common portrayal is that which is conjured by an individual that has been caused great suffering and thereby extracts revenge against the accuser in the form of a curse. This abuser will then have their soul spirited away to hell to suffer endlessly for the rest of eternity. In some instances (such as in `Jigoku Shoujo`) the character who extracts revenge also condemns their own soul to Hell upon death.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5781" parentid="2849" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-08-01">
<name>exorcism</name>
<description>Eviction of demons or other spiritual entities from a person or place which they are believed to have possessed.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5884" parentid="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-03-22">
<name>slow-paced</name>
<description>The story — including its characters and events — develop slowly.
May contain a weak continuity of plot and/or character development. 
Or may be a story telling device to increase the "sense of foreboding" in an anime with thriller or horror setting.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5914" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2012-09-22">
<name>slice of afterlife</name>
<description>Just like Slice of Life, except everyone (or just about everyone) is dead or a spirit, and the story will follow what is considered normal for the characters. Just like slice of life, the story may focus more on the relationships and interactions between the characters and less on plot continuity.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5965" parentid="6247" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="true" verified="false" update="2015-02-10">
<name>incomplete story</name>
<description>The show does not cover all of the original work (if present) or was cancelled prematurely, leaving plot lines unresolved or aborting character development. Sometimes the show runs through all its initially slotted episodes and adapts all of the original work (if applicable) but fails to present a proper ending, leaving viewers wondering whether they`re missing the final episodes.
In some cases, this may overlap with the studio forging an anime-original ending. Such an ending normally manages to allow the show to "finish", but may still suffer from incomplete story issues.
An incomplete storyline is not to be confused with the sequel bait, which is when the story presented by the show is finished but leaves enough room for a sequel to be produced. Sometimes this goes as far as to present a new potential problem in the last few minutes; that is usual for after-credits footage in movies.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5967" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-06-24">
<name>tear jerker</name>
<description>Parts of the anime are so emotionally moving or sad that they bring tears to your eyes.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6028" parentid="2876" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2008-10-12">
<name>Shintoism</name>
<description>Shintoism presents a blessed being or creature that governs over areas of terrain, general space of existence, or an individual object (be it alive or inanimate). Everything has its own "spiritual essence".
Defined as the earliest Japanese thoughts of an unified religion, the word Shinto comes from the Chinese hanzi "神道", combining two kanji: "shin" (神), meaning gods or spirits; and "tō" (道), meaning a philosophical path or study.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6050" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2010-02-11">
<name>human - non-human relationship</name>
<description>The relationship between a human and a non-human — be it alien, or artificial — is explored in this anime.
This usually means between a male human and a female (humanoid) alien or AI (avatar).</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6148" parentid="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>TO BE MOVED TO EPISODE</name>
<description>Tags under this parent tag are going to be moved to episode tags and removed from the anime they`re currently assigned to. They will be blocked from the anime system once that move is complete. Please help with that job if you know what episodes they should be assigned to.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6149" parentid="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>TO BE MOVED TO CHARACTER</name>
<description>Tags under this parent tag are going to be moved to character tags and removed from the anime they`re currently assigned to. They will be blocked from the anime system once that move is complete. Please help with that job if you know what characters they should be assigned to.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6230" parentid="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-20">
<name>cast</name>
</tag>
<tag id="6232" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-10-21">
<name>character related tags which need deleting or merging</name>
</tag>
<tag id="6247" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2014-10-31">
<name>ending tags that need merging</name>
</tag>
</tags>
<characters>
<character id="1806" type="main character in" update="2016-11-23">
<rating votes="401">7.94</rating>
<name>Natsume Takashi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The main character of the story. Like his grandmother, http://anidb.net/ch1808 [Natsume Reiko], Takashi has the ability to see spirits. He has inherited the Book of Friends, a book of names that no one but Reiko, Takashi, and other spirits can read. Because of Takashi`s strong resemblance to Reiko, he is often mistaken for her, causing spirits who hate Reiko to chase him constantly. He decided to dissolve the Book by giving all the names back to their owners. He is accompanied by the spirit http://anidb.net/ch10380 [Madara], nicknamed "Cat" because of the spirit`s appearance, and has promised that to pass the book on to Cat when he dies.</description>
<picture>31015.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="224" picture="79056.jpg">Kamiya Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="1807" type="main character in" update="2016-11-23">
<rating votes="528">8.97</rating>
<name>Nyanko-sensei</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A mysterious feline spirit. Madara was sealed in to a shrine, before accidentally getting released by Natsume. Because he was trapped for so long, Madara has shaped in to a "fortune cat" or manekineko, leading Natsume to nickname him Cat. In this form, other people could see him, leading for Natsume having to ask his guardians if he could keep him. He is a powerful spirit, who protects Natsume from others, and teaches him spells on occasion. They often fight each other, which leads to Natsume punching Madara on the face and knocking him out. Despite his protests of not being a cat, he likes to play with cat toys. Natsume is more respectful to Madara in the anime, calling him "nyanko-sensei" (master cat). Natsume has promised the Book of Friends to him when he dies.</description>
<picture>16394.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="189" picture="23873.jpg">Inoue Kazuhiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="1808" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="95">8.06</rating>
<name>Natsume Reiko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Natsume`s grandmother, from whom he inherited the ability to see spirits. When Reiko was young, she was considered a freak by everyone else because of her ability. Since she believed no human could ever understand her, she turned to the spirits for companionship. Reiko`s power was extraordinarily powerful, and so she bullied spirits in to obeying her by playing games with them. If they lost, she would make them give her their names. Reiko gathered the names in to the Book of Friends, and commanded most spirits, except for Madara, who beat her in a game. Reiko died when she was young, so no one remembered her.</description>
<picture>31023.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="333" picture="18379.jpg">Kobayashi Sanae</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="1809" type="secondary cast in" update="2011-06-22">
<rating votes="94">7.19</rating>
<name>Tanuma Kaname</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Another student that had recently moved into the area. He is sickly and quite susceptible to illnesses. Like Natsume Takashi, he is able to detect spirits, but to a lesser degree limited to seeing merely shadows and sensing slight presence of spirits.</description>
<picture>31017.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="403" picture="74821.jpg">Horie Kazuma</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="1810" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="106">6.19</rating>
<name>Sasada Jun</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The class president of Takashi`s class. Sasada believes that Takashi can see spirits, and constantly asks him questions about it, to which he replies that he doesn`t have such an ability. Much to Takashi`s chagrin, she wants to come along with him when he`s visiting spirits.</description>
<picture>31018.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="38" picture="171532.jpg">Sawashiro Miyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="1811" type="secondary cast in" update="2011-06-22">
<rating votes="74">5.80</rating>
<name>Natori Shuuichi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A man who is also able to see spirits. He is a famous actor and exorcist and has a lizard tattoo that moves around on his body.</description>
<picture>31016.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="194" picture="130580.jpg">Ishida Akira</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="3788" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-11-23">
<rating votes="33">3.86</rating>
<name>Kitamoto Atsushi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Kitamoto Atsushi is a classmate of Natsume, and best friend to Nishimura Satoru. He is a sensible and rational person. Although Natsume initially rejects Atsushi`s overtures of friendship because of his fears of his ability being found out, he eventually becomes friends with Atsushi and Satoru, although they still hang around more with each other than Natsume.</description>
<picture>31020.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2226" picture="23215.jpg">Suganuma Hisayoshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="3789" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-11-23">
<rating votes="33">3.26</rating>
<name>Nishimura Satoru</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Nishimura Satoru is a classmate of Natsume, and best friend to Kitamoto Atsushi. He is funny and easy-going, with a slightly perverted side. Although Natsume initially rejects Satoru`s overtures of friendship because of his fears of his ability being found out, he eventually becomes friends with Satoru and Atsushi, although they still hang around more with each other than Natsume.</description>
<picture>31019.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2225" picture="192115.jpg">Kimura Ryouhei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="3790" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-02-24">
<rating votes="81">8.50</rating>
<name>Fujiwara Touko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>19666.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="229" picture="152363.jpg">Itou Miki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="3791" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-02-24">
<rating votes="59">8.04</rating>
<name>Fujiwara Shigeru</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>19667.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2224" picture="21768.jpg">Itou Eiji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10365" type="appears in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="10">5.34</rating>
<name>Hitotsume no Chuukyuu Youkai</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>31001.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="16701" picture="33550.jpg">Matsuyama Takashi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10366" type="appears in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="10">5.81</rating>
<name>Ushikao no Chuukyuu Youkai</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>31002.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4481" picture="26754.jpg">Shimozaki Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10367" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-11-23">
<rating votes="104">8.30</rating>
<name>Hinoe</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Hinoe is a powerful youkai whose form is a human woman. She is madly in love with Natsume Reiko. Being knowledgeable, she often acts as Natsume Takashi`s mentor. Hinoe enjoys teasing Natsume and Madara.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>30995.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="319" picture="17157.jpg">Okamura Akemi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10368" type="appears in" update="2016-11-27">
<rating votes="6">7.47</rating>
<name>Asagi</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Asagi was a http://anidb.net/t2588 [koto player] in Isozuki Forest for the god, Mibu-sama. She became ill with sickness which causes her body to dry up and crumble off.
She left Lord Mibu`s service and with helping aid from her umbrella holder, http://anidb.net/ch10369 [Akagane], she has stayed alive. She possesses http://anidb.net/ch1806 [Natsume] in order to be able to play the koto one more time for Akagane.
Source: Natsume Yuujinchou Wiki</description>
<picture>31000.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="10" picture="16574.jpg">Noto Mamiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10369" type="appears in" update="2017-01-02">
<rating votes="3">6.85</rating>
<name>Akagane</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Akagane is http://anidb.net/ch10368 [Asagi]`s bodyguard. In the anime, http://anidb.net/ch1806 [Natsume] calls him Janome-san when he refuses to reveal his actual name.
(Janomegasa are a type of traditional umbrella. Janome alone however simply means one-eyed.)
Source: Natsume Yuujinchou Wiki</description>
<picture>30999.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="19" picture="50583.jpg">Imaruoka Atsushi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10370" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="83">7.44</rating>
<name>Hiiragi</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>31013.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="271" picture="171555.jpg">Yukino Satsuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10371" type="appears in" update="2016-11-27">
<rating votes="5">7.66</rating>
<name>Hotaru</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Hotaru is a firefly youkai who in the past had a profound friendship with http://anidb.net/ch34346 [Akifumi], a human that she was in love with. When he was younger, Akifumi could see see her, but lost the ability when he got older. This saddened her deeply.
Source: Natsume Yuujinchou Wiki, edited.</description>
<picture>31014.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="166" picture="23196.jpg">Kuwashima Houko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10372" type="secondary cast in" update="2011-09-11">
<rating votes="58">8.41</rating>
<name>Kogitsune</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>30993.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="237" picture="95027.jpg">Yajima Akiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10373" type="appears in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="6">7.99</rating>
<name>Tsubame</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>30996.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="253" picture="137460.jpg">Yuzuki Ryouka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10374" type="appears in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="2">1.69</rating>
<name>Mikuri</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>30985.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3934" picture="43170.jpg">Yanagihara Tetsuya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10375" type="appears in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="4">4.62</rating>
<name>Santo</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>30994.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="30019" picture="159439.jpg">Hirai Yoshiyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10376" type="appears in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="2">5.11</rating>
<name>Shigure</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>30997.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2585" picture="22579.jpg">Tsuchida Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10377" type="secondary cast in" update="2014-09-05">
<rating votes="34">8.11</rating>
<name>Misuzu</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>30986.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="371" picture="166173.jpg">Kuroda Takaya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10378" type="appears in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="6">6.19</rating>
<name>Tsuyukami</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>30998.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="28" picture="23184.jpg">Aono Takeshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10380" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-07-13">
<rating votes="156">9.19</rating>
<name>Madara</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>31024.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="189" picture="23873.jpg">Inoue Kazuhiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34319" type="appears in" update="2016-11-27">
<rating votes="4">2.38</rating>
<name>Hishigaki</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195194.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="36" picture="25827.jpg">Saitou Kimiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34320" type="appears in" update="2016-11-26">
<rating votes="2">1.72</rating>
<name>Choumimi no Youkai</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195195.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4726" picture="54694.jpg">Kawamoto Kunihiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34321" type="appears in" update="2016-11-27">
<rating votes="2">8.00</rating>
<name>Hana</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195153.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="21661" picture="55836.jpg">Kita Michie</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34322" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="2">3.33</rating>
<name>Susugi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195150.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="64" picture="173421.jpg">Yasumoto Hiroki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34323" type="appears in" update="2016-11-26">
<rating votes="49">8.00</rating>
<name>Natsume Takashi (Shounen Jidai)</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195196.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="441" picture="171611.jpg">Fujimura Ayumi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34324" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="6">4.66</rating>
<name>Tanuma no Chichi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195143.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="455" picture="17356.jpg">Matsumoto Yasunori</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34334" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="14">6.53</rating>
<name>Joshikousei Nyanko-sensei</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195142.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="333" picture="18379.jpg">Kobayashi Sanae</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34335" type="appears in" update="2016-11-27">
<rating votes="6">4.83</rating>
<name>Kappa</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Kappa, whose name remains unknown, is a youkai whom http://anidb.net/a5787 [Natsume] usually helped when he was dehydrated. Because of that, kappa always tried to help Natsume in any way he could.</description>
<picture>79827.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="9360" picture="171916.jpg">Chikiri Kyouko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34338" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="2">6.13</rating>
<name>Tarusaru</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195146.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2365" picture="22143.jpg">Takase Akimitsu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34339" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="2">3.33</rating>
<name>Taniozaki</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195147.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3141" picture="65575.jpg">Tsuruoka Satoshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34341" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="6">2.05</rating>
<name>Hitotsume no Akaoni</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195158.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="16701" picture="33550.jpg">Matsuyama Takashi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34342" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="6">2.84</rating>
<name>Gozu no Aooni</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195159.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4481" picture="26754.jpg">Shimozaki Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34346" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="2">8.86</rating>
<name>Sugino Akifumi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195152.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="373" picture="191382.jpg">Hamada Kenji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34349" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="10">6.18</rating>
<name>Sasago</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195157.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1742" picture="20193.jpg">Honda Chieko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34350" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="10">4.05</rating>
<name>Urihime</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195156.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4705" picture="158550.jpg">Higuchi Akari</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34351" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="4">5.77</rating>
<name>Natori Shuuichi (Shounen Jidai)</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195155.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="142" picture="68482.jpg">Ooura Fuyuka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="34353" type="appears in" update="2016-11-25">
<rating votes="2">7.10</rating>
<name>Tamiko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195140.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1628" picture="19670.jpg">Ishige Sawa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="38206" type="appears in" update="2016-11-26">
<rating votes="3">2.36</rating>
<name>Shinseki no Obasan</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>195197.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="9360" picture="171916.jpg">Chikiri Kyouko</seiyuu>
</character>
</characters>
<episodes>
<episode id="91602" update="2008-06-26">
<epno type="4">T1</epno>
<length>2</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Natsume Yuujinchou PV</title>
</episode>
<episode id="91904" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">1</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-07-08</airdate>
<rating votes="19">6.48</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">猫と友人帳</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Cat and the Book of Friends</title>
<title xml:lang="ar">القط و كتاب الاصدقاء</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Neko to Yuujinchou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="91929" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">2</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-07-15</airdate>
<rating votes="15">7.33</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">露神の祠</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Dew God`s Small Shrine</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Tsuyukami no Hokora</title>
</episode>
<episode id="91930" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">3</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-07-22</airdate>
<rating votes="14">7.63</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">八ツ原の怪人</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Mysterious Person at the Eight Fields</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Yatsuhara no Kaijin</title>
</episode>
<episode id="91931" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">4</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-07-29</airdate>
<rating votes="11">7.25</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">時雨と少女</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Shigure and the Girl</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Shigure to Shoujo</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92242" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">5</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-05</airdate>
<rating votes="11">5.82</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">心色の切符</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Heart-Colored Ticket</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kokoro-iro no Kippu</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92383" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">6</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-12</airdate>
<rating votes="14">8.82</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">水底の燕</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Swallow at the Water Bottom</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Suitei no Tsubame</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92544" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">7</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-19</airdate>
<rating votes="14">8.59</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">子狐のぼうし</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Little Fox`s Hat</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kogitsune no Boushi</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92563" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">10</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-09</airdate>
<rating votes="12">7.12</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">アサギの琴</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Asagi`s Koto</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Asagi no Koto</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92564" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">9</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-02</airdate>
<rating votes="12">7.13</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">あやかし祓い</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Ayakashi Purification</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Ayakashi Harai</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92565" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">8</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-26</airdate>
<rating votes="13">7.50</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">儚い光</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Fleeting Light</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Hakanai Hikari</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92793" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">13</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-30</airdate>
<rating votes="12">8.82</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">秋の夜宴</title>
<title xml:lang="en">An Autumn Night Banquet</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Aki no Yaen</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92794" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">12</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-23</airdate>
<rating votes="11">8.46</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">五日印</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Five Day Mark</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Itsuka Shirushi</title>
</episode>
<episode id="92795" update="2016-11-21">
<epno type="1">11</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-16</airdate>
<rating votes="12">6.86</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ニャンコ徒然帳</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Nyanko`s Book of Boredom</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Nyanko Tsurezurechou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="105667" update="2016-03-27">
<epno type="3">C1</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2008-07-08</airdate>
<rating votes="2">5.30</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Opening</title>
</episode>
<episode id="105668" update="2016-03-27">
<epno type="3">C2</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2008-07-08</airdate>
<rating votes="2">5.30</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending</title>
</episode>
<episode id="162496" update="2014-09-02">
<epno type="2">S3</epno>
<length>15</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Live DVD Special 3</title>
</episode>
<episode id="162497" update="2014-09-02">
<epno type="2">S2</epno>
<length>20</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Live DVD Special 2</title>
</episode>
<episode id="162498" update="2014-09-02">
<epno type="2">S1</epno>
<length>15</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Live DVD Special 1</title>
</episode>
</episodes>
</anime>
